let questions = [
    {
        "numb": 1,
        "question": "The goal of balance is to bring your mind and body back into?",
        "answer": "(A) Stress management",
        "options": [
            "(A) Stress management",
            "(B) Group management",
            "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 2,
        "question": "___ are likely to cause stress in countries which suffer from political uncertainties.",
        "answer": "(B) Political factors",
        "options": [
            "(A) Economic factors",
            "(B) Political factors",
            "(C) Technological factors",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 3,
        "question": "People with ___ profile experience considerable stress.",
        "answer": "(A) personality A",
        "options": [
            "(A) personality A",
            "(B) personality B",
            "(C) personality C",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 4,
        "question": "Stress can play a part in problems such as:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) high blood pressure",
            "(B) depression",
            "(C) anxiety",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 5,
        "question": "Burnout is a psychological process resulting from work stress that results in:",
        "answer": "All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) emotional exhaustion",
            "(B) depersonalization",
            "(C) feelings of decreased accomplishment",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 6,
        "question": "\"A leader is born and is not made\" is a:",
        "answer": "(B) born leadership theory",
        "options": [
            "(A) charismatic leadership theory",
            "(B) born leadership theory",
            "(C) transformational leadership theory",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 7,
        "question": "Which of the leadership theories proposed that \"there is no one best leadership style\"?",
        "answer": "(C) situational theory",
        "options": [
            "(A) trait theory",
            "(B) behavioral theory",
            "(C) situational theory",
            "(D) charismatic theory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 8,
        "question": "Management Grid is developed by:",
        "answer": "(A) R. R. Blake and J. S. Mouton",
        "options": [
            "(A) R. R. Blake and J. S. Mouton",
            "(B) W.J. Reddin",
            "(C) Elton Mayo",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 9,
        "question": "Who has identified leadership style on two dimensions?",
        "answer": "(A) Fiedler",
        "options": [
            "(A) Fiedler",
            "(B) Elton Mayo",
            "(C) Robbins",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 10,
        "question": "___ is the pattern of behaviour which a leader adopts in influencing the behavior of his followers.",
        "answer": "(B) Leadership style",
        "options": [
            "(A) Motivational style",
            "(B) Leadership style",
            "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 11,
        "question": "Which is the part of an organization?",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Informal organization",
            "(B) Formal organization",
            "(C) Physical environment of the work situation",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 12,
        "question": "What is true about formal group?",
        "answer": "(C) All message pass through a chain of commands",
        "options": [
            "(A) It is stable and continues for a longer period.",
            "(B) Formal groups are quite large.",
            "(C) All message pass through a chain of commands.",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 13,
        "question": "Charismatic Authority is derived from the:",
        "answer": "(B) Power",
        "options": [
            "(A) Value",
            "(B) Power",
            "(C) Religion",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 14,
        "question": "\"Leadership is the activity of influencing people to strive willingly for group objectives.\" This statement is given by:",
        "answer": "(A) George R. Terry",
        "options": [
            "(A) George R. Terry",
            "(B) Davis, Keith",
            "(C) Rensis Likert",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 15,
        "question": "Which is not correct about the nature of leadership?",
        "answer": "(D) Unity of accounting",
        "options": [
            "(A) Dynamic process",
            "(B) It is personal quality",
            "(C) Ideal conduct",
            "(D) Unity of accounting"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 16,
        "question": "The positive motivators are:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Delegation",
            "(B) Rewards",
            "(C) Cash Remuneration",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 17,
        "question": "Which of the following is a large determinant of personality as per Luthans?",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Cultural contribution",
            "(B) Biological contribution",
            "(C) Situation",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 18,
        "question": "The reason for formation of group is:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Affiliation",
            "(B) Power",
            "(C) Goal Achievement",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 19,
        "question": "The characteristics of group includes:",
        "answer": "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
        "options": [
            "(A) Activities",
            "(B) Informal leadership",
            "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 20,
        "question": "The function of informal groups consists:",
        "answer": "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
        "options": [
            "(A) Determination of norms",
            "(B) Personality development",
            "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 21,
        "question": "Which is a deviation of group norms?",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Group control",
            "(B) Socialisation",
            "(C) Hierarchy",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 22,
        "question": "A group whose members have complementary skills and are committed to a common purpose or goals for which they hold themselves mutually accountable is called:",
        "answer": "(A) A team",
        "options": [
            "(A) A team",
            "(B) Motion",
            "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 23,
        "question": "Following are types of teams:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Problem-solving team",
            "(B) Self-managed team",
            "(C) Cross-functional team",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 24,
        "question": "How many stages of team development are there according to Bruce W. Tuckman?",
        "answer": "(A) 5",
        "options": [
            "(A) 5",
            "(B) 3",
            "(C) 2",
            "(D) 1"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 25,
        "question": "According to Richard Beckhard the purpose of team building is:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) to analyze the way work is performed.",
            "(B) to examine the way a group is working and its processes.",
            "(C) to examine relationships among the people doing the work.",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 26,
        "question": "Brainstorming is a technique used for:",
        "answer": "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
        "options": [
            "(A) Problem solving",
            "(B) Idea generation",
            "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 27,
        "question": "The individual coping strategies that deal with stress at work are:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Time management",
            "(B) Exercise",
            "(C) Meditation and relaxation",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 28,
        "question": "Organizational coping strategies which deal with the stress at work are:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Role clarity",
            "(B) Supportive climate",
            "(C) Company-wide programs",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 29,
        "question": "Which of the following indicate country-wide program?",
        "answer": "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
        "options": [
            "(A) Job enrichment",
            "(B) Training and development",
            "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 30,
        "question": "Which analysis helps to understand the strength and weakness of an organization?",
        "answer": "(B) SWOT analysis",
        "options": [
            "(A) Business analysis",
            "(B) SWOT analysis",
            "(C) Environment analysis",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 31,
        "question": "OB is the study of ___ in the organization.",
        "answer": "(B) Human Behavior",
        "options": [
            "(A) Human",
            "(B) Human Behavior",
            "(C) Employer",
            "(D) Employee"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 32,
        "question": "Scope of OB does not include:",
        "answer": "(D) Technology",
        "options": [
            "(A) Perception",
            "(B) Job title",
            "(C) Leadership",
            "(D) Technology"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 33,
        "question": "The book 'The Psychology of Management' was published by:",
        "answer": "(C) William Gilbreth",
        "options": [
            "(A) Robert Owen",
            "(B) Henry Fayol",
            "(C) William Gilbreth",
            "(D) F.W. Taylor"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 34,
        "question": "The main forces affecting organizational behavior are:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Technology",
            "(B) Environment",
            "(C) Human",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 35,
        "question": "In the modern context, challenges for organizational behavior are:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Globalization",
            "(B) Employee expectation",
            "(C) Globalization",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 36,
        "question": "Organizational behavior is:",
        "answer": "(C) A Science as well as an Art",
        "options": [
            "(A) An art",
            "(B) A Science",
            "(C) A Science as well as an Art",
            "(D) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 37,
        "question": "According to the scientists of organizational behavior, how are the organizations?",
        "answer": "(B) Dynamics and ever changing",
        "options": [
            "(A) Static",
            "(B) Dynamics and ever changing",
            "(C) Researching",
            "(D) Processing"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 38,
        "question": "Which of the following forms the basis for the Autocratic model of organizational behavior?",
        "answer": "(A) Power",
        "options": [
            "(A) Power",
            "(B) Obedience",
            "(C) Authority",
            "(D) Dependence on Boss"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 39,
        "question": "The supportive model of organizational behavior depends on:",
        "answer": "(C) Leadership",
        "options": [
            "(A) Power",
            "(B) Economic Resources",
            "(C) Leadership",
            "(D) Authority"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 40,
        "question": "The collegial model is basically an extension of:",
        "answer": "(A) Supportive model",
        "options": [
            "(A) Supportive model",
            "(B) Custodial model",
            "(C) Autocratic model",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 41,
        "question": "\"Might is right\" is the motto of:",
        "answer": "(A) Autocratic model",
        "options": [
            "(A) Autocratic model",
            "(B) Custodial model",
            "(C) Supportive model",
            "(D) Collegial model"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 42,
        "question": "Which of the following is the emerging challenge and opportunity in organizational behavior?",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Improving quality and productivity",
            "(B) Total quality management",
            "(C) Managing workforce diversity",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 43,
        "question": "What are the factors that are challenging for organizations?",
        "answer": "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
        "options": [
            "(A) Turnover",
            "(B) Lack of productivity",
            "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 44,
        "question": "___ is the process by which an individual becomes aware of and interprets information about the environment.",
        "answer": "(B) Perception",
        "options": [
            "(A) Personality",
            "(B) Perception",
            "(C) Motivation",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 45,
        "question": "Judging people on the basis of the characteristics of the group to which they belong is called:",
        "answer": "(C) Stereotyping",
        "options": [
            "(A) Selective perception",
            "(B) Halo effect",
            "(C) Stereotyping",
            "(D) Attribution"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 46,
        "question": "Perception is the:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Intellectual process",
            "(B) Psychological process",
            "(C) Subjective process",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 47,
        "question": "The first stage in perceptual process is:",
        "answer": "(A) Stimuli",
        "options": [
            "(A) Stimuli",
            "(B) Perceptual outputs",
            "(C) Characteristics of perceiver",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 48,
        "question": "What are the 3 levels of perception?",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) The heart",
            "(B) Mind",
            "(C) Matter",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 49,
        "question": "Following are the types of values:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Theoretical",
            "(B) Aesthetic",
            "(C) Social",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 50,
        "question": "Value which is related to means for achieving desired ends is called:",
        "answer": "(B) Instrumental value",
        "options": [
            "(A) Terminal value",
            "(B) Instrumental value",
            "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 51,
        "question": "A person learns and develops values because of:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Social factors",
            "(B) Cultural factors",
            "(C) Religious factors",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 52,
        "question": "Attitude affects behavior at a different level.",
        "answer": "(C) Behavior",
        "options": [
            "(A) Relations",
            "(B) Perception",
            "(C) Behavior",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 53,
        "question": "Attitude is dependent on the factor:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Psychological",
            "(B) Economic",
            "(C) Organizational",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 54,
        "question": "Liking or disliking of any particular person, item or event is called:",
        "answer": "(A) Evaluating component of attitude",
        "options": [
            "(A) Evaluating component of attitude",
            "(B) Cognitive component of attitude",
            "(C) Behavioral component of attitude",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 55,
        "question": "Which of the following is not included in job-related attitude defined by Stephen Robbins?",
        "answer": "Job performance",
        "options": [
            "(A) Job performance",
            "(B) Organizational commitment",
            "(C) Job satisfaction",
            "Job involvement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 56,
        "question": "The foundation or base of the components of job-related attitude is:",
        "answer": "(C) Individual attitude",
        "options": [
            "(A) Job satisfaction",
            "(B) Job performance",
            "(C) Individual attitude",
            "(D) Behavior"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 57,
        "question": "Employees describe work and can be made to work by coercion:",
        "answer": "(A) Theory X",
        "options": [
            "(A) Theory X",
            "(B) Theory Y",
            "(C) Theory Z",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 58,
        "question": "Which theory is based on democratic system and humanitarian values?",
        "answer": "(B) Theory Y",
        "options": [
            "(A) Theory X",
            "(B) Theory Y",
            "(C) Vroom's expectancy theory",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 59,
        "question": "Theory X and Theory Y were proposed by:",
        "answer": "(C) McGregor",
        "options": [
            "(A) Herzberg",
            "(B) Maslow",
            "(C) McGregor",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 60,
        "question": "How do managers motivate employees using Theory Y?",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Allow them to work on their own initiative",
            "(B) Give them responsibility",
            "(C) Empowering them to make decisions",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 61,
        "question": "What are the factors affecting motivation?",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Growth",
            "(B) Advancement",
            "(C) Achievement and Responsibility",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 62,
        "question": "Professionals use motivation theories to:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Increase production and profit",
            "(B) Increase employee retention rate",
            "(C) Increase employee satisfaction level",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 63,
        "question": "Use of incentives and disincentives to promote desired behavior find their reference in the .......... to motivation.",
        "answer": "(A) \"Carrot and Stick\" approach",
        "options": [
            "(A) \"Carrot and Stick\" approach",
            "(B) Goodwill approach",
            "(C) Employee-oriented approach",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 64,
        "question": "Who is the developer of 'Two-factor theory' of Motivation?",
        "answer": "(A) Herzberg",
        "options": [
            "(A) Herzberg",
            "(B) A.H. Maslow",
            "(C) Taylor",
            "(D) Bernard"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 65,
        "question": "Ego includes:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Parent Ego state",
            "(B) Adult Ego state",
            "(C) Child Ego state",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 66,
        "question": "According to Freud the psychic functions of ego includes:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Judgment",
            "(B) Reality testing",
            "(C) Planning",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 67,
        "question": "Motivation includes:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Job Enrichment",
            "(B) Job Enlargement",
            "(C) Job Rotation",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 68,
        "question": "Which is not Maslow's need?",
        "answer": "(B) Control",
        "options": [
            "(A) Self-actualization",
            "(B) Control",
            "(C) Esteem",
            "(D) Safety"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 69,
        "question": "Human motives are developed by:",
        "answer": "(A) A. H. Maslow",
        "options": [
            "(A) A. H. Maslow",
            "(B) McGregor",
            "(C) Fayol",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 70,
        "question": "Hygiene factors relating to the work content include:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Company policy and administration",
            "(B) Supervision",
            "(C) Status",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 71,
        "question": "Motivation represents a person and how he behaves in response to environmental variables.",
        "answer": "(A) Personality",
        "options": [
            "(A) Personality",
            "(B) Motivation",
            "(C) Leadership",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 72,
        "question": "Personality is a concept that deals with the growth and development of a person as a whole.",
        "answer": "(A) Psychological",
        "options": [
            "(A) Psychological",
            "(B) Natural",
            "(C) Leadership",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 73,
        "question": "Personality of a person is characterized by the following features:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) It represents traits of a person.",
            "(B) It represents a stable pattern of behavior.",
            "(C) It is genetic as well as acquired from the environment.",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 74,
        "question": "Personality is affected by the following factors:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Biological factors",
            "(B) Cultural factors",
            "(C) Situational factors",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 75,
        "question": "The biological system of a person influences his behavior, including:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Heredity",
            "(B) Brain",
            "(C) Physical features",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 76,
        "question": "Family and social factors shape a person's personality through the process of:",
        "answer": "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
        "options": [
            "(A) Socialization",
            "(B) Identification",
            "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 77,
        "question": "Temperament is a non-intellectual personality trait.",
        "answer": "(A) Non-intellectual",
        "options": [
            "(A) Non-intellectual",
            "(B) Leadership",
            "(C) Heredity",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 78,
        "question": "Which of the following belongs to Big Five personality traits?",
        "answer": "(C) Emotional stability",
        "options": [
            "(A) Locus of control",
            "(B) Type A and Type B behavior",
            "(C) Emotional stability",
            "(D) Machiavellianism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 79,
        "question": "Personality traits are enduring characteristics that describe an individual's behavior.",
        "answer": "(A) Individual's behavior",
        "options": [
            "(A) Individual's behavior",
            "(B) Individual's habits",
            "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 80,
        "question": ".......... deals with the belief of people as to whether they control the events or the events control them.",
        "answer": "(B) Locus of control",
        "options": [
            "(A) Openness",
            "(B) Locus of control",
            "(C) Self-esteem",
            "(D) Self-monitoring"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 81,
        "question": ".......... is a self-help assessment test which helps people gain insights about how they work and learn.",
        "answer": "(B) Myers-Briggs type indicator",
        "options": [
            "(A) Self-monitoring",
            "(B) Myers-Briggs type indicator",
            "(C) Extroversion",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 82,
        "question": "A highly .......... person is focused, organized, systematic, disciplined, and thorough.",
        "answer": "(A) Conscientious",
        "options": [
            "(A) Conscientious",
            "(B) Emotional stability",
            "(C) Risk-taking",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 83,
        "question": "Personality that is competitive and sets high standards for themselves is called:",
        "answer": "(A) Type A personality",
        "options": [
            "(A) Type A personality",
            "(B) Type B personality",
            "(C) Type C personality",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 84,
        "question": "People with .......... are creative, accept new ideas, and are willing to give up their existing thoughts.",
        "answer": "(B) Openness",
        "options": [
            "(A) Agreeableness",
            "(B) Openness",
            "(C) Emotional stability",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 85,
        "question": "Personality traits can be assessed in two ways:",
        "answer": "(A) Personality inventory and rating scale",
        "options": [
            "(A) Personality inventory and rating scale",
            "(B) Endomorph and mesomorph",
            "(C) Ego and superego",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 86,
        "question": "The .......... theory categorizes people into different categories on the basis of physical attributes and psychological factors.",
        "answer": "(B) Type",
        "options": [
            "(A) Trait",
            "(B) Type",
            "(C) ERG",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 87,
        "question": "Two important \"type\" theories are:",
        "answer": "(A) Physiognomy and extrovert-introvert",
        "options": [
            "(A) Physiognomy and extrovert-introvert",
            "(B) Self-theory and myself theory",
            "(C) Social learning theory and market learning theory",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 88,
        "question": "Which theory asserts that personality of a person depends upon his:",
        "answer": "(B) Traits theory",
        "options": [
            "(A) Social learning theory",
            "(B) Traits theory",
            "(C) Type theory",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 89,
        "question": ".......... believe in use of power and politics in whatever way possible.",
        "answer": "(B) High Machs",
        "options": [
            "(A) Low Machs",
            "(B) High Machs",
            "(C) Authoritarian",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 90,
        "question": "Type B personality do not take work pressure and work at steady pace.",
        "answer": "(B) Type B",
        "options": [
            "(A) Type A",
            "(B) Type B",
            "(C) Locus of control",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 91,
        "question": "From an individual's point of view, .......... is our body's physical, mental, and chemical reaction.",
        "answer": "(B) Stress",
        "options": [
            "(A) Fatigue",
            "(B) Stress",
            "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 92,
        "question": "As per medical explanation, the term stress is the body's general response to:",
        "answer": "(C) Environmental",
        "options": [
            "(A) Social situations",
            "(B) Political situations",
            "(C) Environmental factors",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 93,
        "question": "According to .........., \"Job stress is a condition arising from the interaction of people and their jobs and characterized by changes within people that force them to deviate from their normal functioning.\"",
        "answer": "(B) T.A. Bechr and J.E. Newman",
        "options": [
            "(A) D. McGregor",
            "(B) T.A. Bechr and J.E. Newman",
            "(C) Alford Butler",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 94,
        "question": "Symptoms of stress are:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) High blood pressure",
            "(B) Emotional instability",
            "(C) Digestion problems",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 95,
        "question": "Which of the following is a short-range physical disorder?",
        "answer": "(A) Upset stomach",
        "options": [
            "(A) Upset stomach",
            "(B) Stomach ulcer",
            "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 96,
        "question": "Which of the following is an individual stressor?",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Job concern",
            "(B) Changes in life structure",
            "(C) Role characteristics",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 97,
        "question": "Which of the following stressors can be categorized as group stressors?",
        "answer": "(A) Lack of Group Cohesiveness",
        "options": [
            "(A) Lack of Group Cohesiveness",
            "(B) Organizational Climate",
            "(C) Both (A) and (B)",
            "(D) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 98,
        "question": "Which of the following is categorized as organizational stressors?",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Organizational process",
            "(B) Organizational structure",
            "(C) Physical conditions",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 99,
        "question": "Extra-organizational stressors can be categorized into factors such as:",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Political",
            "(B) Economic",
            "(C) Technological",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 100,
        "question": "Which of the following time management aids helps to reduce stress?",
        "answer": "(D) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(A) Create a balanced schedule",
            "(B) Prioritize tasks",
            "(C) Delegate responsibility",
            "(D) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 101,
        "question": "Downward communication is used for-",
        "answer": "(c) Both",
        "options": [
            "(a) Order",
            "(b) Instruction",
            "(c) Both",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 102,
        "question": "Relationship between job and performance is.",
        "answer": "(b) Positive",
        "options": [
            "(a) Negative",
            "(b) Positive",
            "(c) Both",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 103,
        "question": "Factors which affect job satisfaction.",
        "answer": "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
        "options": [
            "(a) Personal characteristics",
            "(b) Work behavior",
            "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 104,
        "question": "Span of supervision depends upon.",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Time available",
            "(b) Communication techniques",
            "(c) Rate of change in policy",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 105,
        "question": "Which of the following is important for effective supervision?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Leadership",
            "(b) Communication.",
            "(c) Delegation of authority",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 106,
        "question": "Step to handle burnout.",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Identifying",
            "(b) Examine mental well-being",
            "(c) Organization",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 107,
        "question": "BOSS means.",
        "answer": "(c) Burnout stress syndrome",
        "options": [
            "(a) Burnout sad stop",
            "(b) Boss office and stress symptoms",
            "(c) Burnout stress syndrome",
            "(d) Burnout, stop supply"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 108,
        "question": "Which of the following is not an individual stress-reducing strategy?",
        "answer": "(d) Creating a supportive organizational climate",
        "options": [
            "(a) Exercise",
            "(b) Relation",
            "(c) Networking",
            "(d) Creating a supportive organizational climate"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 109,
        "question": "Crime is a type of social stressors.",
        "answer": "(d) Interpersonal & environmental",
        "options": [
            "(a) Social economic & political",
            "(b) Family",
            "(c) Job & career",
            "(d) Interpersonal & environmental"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 110,
        "question": "Death or illness in the family is a type of social stressor.",
        "answer": "(b) Family",
        "options": [
            "(a) Social economic & political",
            "(b) Family",
            "(c) Job & career",
            "(d) Interpersonal & environmental"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 111,
        "question": "Workload is a type of social stressor.",
        "answer": "(c) Job & career",
        "options": [
            "(a) Social economic & political",
            "(b) Family",
            "(c) Job & career",
            "(d) Interpersonal & environmental"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 112,
        "question": "Stress has.",
        "answer": "(c) Positive and negative effects",
        "options": [
            "(a) Only positive effects",
            "(b) Only negative effects",
            "(c) Positive and negative effects",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 113,
        "question": "The resources of group members depend upon.",
        "answer": "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
        "options": [
            "(a) Ability",
            "(b) Personal characteristics",
            "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 114,
        "question": "Task group is.",
        "answer": "(a) Formal group",
        "options": [
            "(a) Formal group",
            "(b) Informal group",
            "(c) External group",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 115,
        "question": "Which of the following is/are informal groups?",
        "answer": "(b) Friendship group",
        "options": [
            "(a) Interest group",
            "(b) Friendship group",
            "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 116,
        "question": "Also known as 'great-man old theory'.",
        "answer": "(a) Trait theory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Trait theory",
            "(b) Situation theory",
            "(c) Charismatic theory",
            "(d) None of all"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 117,
        "question": "Which of the following qualities which the future leadership possess?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Career developer",
            "(b) Proper vision",
            "(c) Time management",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 118,
        "question": "Which of the following is not considered as a leadership style?",
        "answer": "(c) Society oriented",
        "options": [
            "(a) Task oriented",
            "(b) Employee oriented",
            "(c) Society oriented",
            "(d) All of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 119,
        "question": "Leadership qualities are.",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Endowed with intelligence and strength of mind",
            "(b) Liberal",
            "(c) Retention",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 120,
        "question": "Modern organizations must be.",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Team oriented",
            "(b) Knowledge and learning oriented",
            "(c) Alliance and partnership oriented",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 121,
        "question": "Relates environment to a specific organization structure.",
        "answer": "(a) Contingency theory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Contingency theory",
            "(b) System",
            "(c) Decision making",
            "(d) All of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 122,
        "question": "Organization theories are.",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Classical",
            "(b) System",
            "(c) Decision making",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 123,
        "question": "Principal of perceptual organization.",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Figure ground",
            "(b) Perceptual context",
            "(c) Perceptual grouping",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 124,
        "question": "X motivation theory was given by.",
        "answer": "(a) McGregor",
        "options": [
            "(a) McGregor",
            "(b) Herbert Simon",
            "(c) Both",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 125,
        "question": "Perception elements involve.",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Selection of stimuli",
            "(b) Organization of stimuli",
            "(c) Interpretation of stimuli",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 126,
        "question": "External factors affecting perception do not include.",
        "answer": "(c) Psychological factors",
        "options": [
            "(a) The target",
            "(b) The situation",
            "(c) Psychological factors",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 127,
        "question": "Internal factors affecting perception include.",
        "answer": "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
        "options": [
            "(a) Sensory limits and threshold",
            "(b) Psychological factors",
            "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 128,
        "question": "Which is not a sign of high moral?",
        "answer": "(c) Lot of tension",
        "options": [
            "(a) Dependability",
            "(b) Strength",
            "(c) Lot of tension",
            "(d) Confidence and demotions"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 129,
        "question": "Attitude refers to a feeling and belief of an individual or group people.",
        "answer": "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
        "options": [
            "(a) Positive",
            "(b) Negative",
            "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 130,
        "question": "Global diversity conditions are.",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Political condition",
            "(b) Social condition",
            "(c) Economic condition",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 131,
        "question": "Distance between two social systems is known as.",
        "answer": "(a) Culture shock",
        "options": [
            "(a) Culture shock",
            "(b) Culture change",
            "(c) Culture contingencies",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 132,
        "question": "Diversity in OB can be in.",
        "answer": "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
        "options": [
            "(a) Culture",
            "(b) Global",
            "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 133,
        "question": "Organizational behavior helps.",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Effective use of human resources",
            "(b) Understand organization",
            "(c) Maintain good organization culture",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 134,
        "question": "In which model employee orientation is responsible behavior.",
        "answer": "(d) Collegial",
        "options": [
            "(a) Autocratic",
            "(b) Supportive",
            "(c) Custodial",
            "(d) Collegial"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 135,
        "question": "In which model performance result is moderate enthusiasm.",
        "answer": "(b) Supportive",
        "options": [
            "(a) Autocratic",
            "(b) Supportive",
            "(c) Custodial",
            "(d) Collegial"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 136,
        "question": "In which model performance result is passive cooperation.",
        "answer": "(c) Custodial",
        "options": [
            "(a) Autocratic",
            "(b) Supportive",
            "(c) Custodial",
            "(d) Collegial"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 137,
        "question": "In which model managerial orientation is support.",
        "answer": "(b) Supportive",
        "options": [
            "(a) Autocratic",
            "(b) Supportive",
            "(c) Custodial",
            "(d) Collegial"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 138,
        "question": "Which model embodies the team concept?",
        "answer": "(a) Collegial model",
        "options": [
            "(a) Collegial model",
            "(b) Supportive model",
            "(c) Autocratic model",
            "(d) Custodial model"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 139,
        "question": "In which model is the managerial orientation towards money to pay wage and benefits.",
        "answer": "(d) Custodial model",
        "options": [
            "(a) Collegial model",
            "(b) Supportive model",
            "(c) Autocratic model",
            "(d) Custodial model"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 140,
        "question": "The model which is originated from the principle of supportive relationship is.",
        "answer": "(b) Supportive model",
        "options": [
            "(a) Collegial model",
            "(b) Supportive model",
            "(c) Autocratic model",
            "(d) Custodial model"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 141,
        "question": "In which model is employee orientation obedience to boss, not respect for manager.",
        "answer": "(c) Autocratic model",
        "options": [
            "(a) Supportive model",
            "(b) Collegial model",
            "(c) Autocratic model",
            "(d) Custodial model"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 142,
        "question": "What are the features of organizational behavior?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Part of management",
            "(b) Goal oriented",
            "(c) Interdisciplinary",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 143,
        "question": "From 1928-1930, which aspect of the Hawthorne study was conducted?",
        "answer": "(d) Mass writing room study",
        "options": [
            "(a) Relay room",
            "(b) Bank wiring room study",
            "(c) Illumination",
            "(d) Mass writing room study"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 144,
        "question": "Relay room experiment was conducted from.",
        "answer": "(a) 1927 to 1932",
        "options": [
            "(a) 1927 to 1932",
            "(b) 1928 to 1933",
            "(c) 1827 to 1832",
            "(d) 1999 to 2001"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 145,
        "question": "Illumination experiments were conducted from.",
        "answer": "(d) 1923 to 1931",
        "options": [
            "(a) 1924 to 1933",
            "(b) 1999 to 2005",
            "(c) 1911 to 1922",
            "(d) 1923 to 1931"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 146,
        "question": "Which company conducted the Hawthorne study?",
        "answer": "(b) Western electric co.",
        "options": [
            "(a) Eastern electric co.",
            "(b) Western electric co.",
            "(c) Southern electric co.",
            "(d) Northern electric co."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 147,
        "question": "How long were those experiments conducted from?",
        "answer": "(a) 1924 to 1932",
        "options": [
            "(a) 1924 to 1932",
            "(b) 1999 to 2005",
            "(c) 1911 to 1922",
            "(d) 1923 to 1931"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 148,
        "question": "Autocratic model depends upon.",
        "answer": "(c) Power",
        "options": [
            "(a) Rewards",
            "(b) Support",
            "(c) Power",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 149,
        "question": "The model dependent upon economic resources is.",
        "answer": "(b) Custodial",
        "options": [
            "(a) Autocratic",
            "(b) Custodial",
            "(c) Collegial",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 150,
        "question": "\"Human beings are lazy and must be carefully handled.\" This assumption is given by......",
        "answer": "(d) Taylor",
        "options": [
            "(a) Weber",
            "(b) Mayo",
            "(c) Hamilton",
            "(d) Taylor"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 151,
        "question": "Organizational conflict can occur at.",
        "answer": "(c) Both",
        "options": [
            "(a) Interpersonal level",
            "(b) Intra-personal level",
            "(c) Both",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 152,
        "question": "Which of the following forms the basis for the autocratic model of OB?",
        "answer": "(c) Power",
        "options": [
            "(a) Obedience",
            "(b) Authority",
            "(c) Power",
            "(d) Dependence on boss"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 153,
        "question": "The field of organizational behaviour is primarily concerned with.",
        "answer": "(a) The behaviour of individual and groups",
        "options": [
            "(a) The behaviour of individual and groups",
            "(b) How resources are effectively managed",
            "(c) Control processes and interactions between organizations external context",
            "(d) Both (a) and (b)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 154,
        "question": "The field of organizational behaviour examines such questions as the nature of leadership, effective term development and:",
        "answer": "(a) Interpersonal conflict resolution; motivation of individuals",
        "options": [
            "(a) Interpersonal conflict resolution; motivation of individuals",
            "(b) Organizational management",
            "(c) Long-term planning",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 155,
        "question": "Organizational behaviour is a field of study backed by a body associated with growing concern for people at the workplace.",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Theory",
            "(b) Research",
            "(c) Application",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 156,
        "question": "According to Maslow, which of the following is a basic need?",
        "answer": "(a) Food, water",
        "options": [
            "(a) Food, water",
            "(b) Friends",
            "(c) Leader",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 157,
        "question": "The leadership style is an expression of the leader's trust in the abilities of his subordinates.",
        "answer": "(b) Delegative",
        "options": [
            "(a) Participative",
            "(b) Delegative",
            "(c) Authoritarian",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 158,
        "question": "We can define as activities people perform to acquire, enhance, and use power and other resources to obtain their preferred outcomes in a situation of uncertainty or disagreement.",
        "answer": "(a) Organizational politics",
        "options": [
            "(a) Organizational politics",
            "(b) Executing authority",
            "(c) Collective bargaining",
            "(d) Position power"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 159,
        "question": "A study of human behaviour in organizational settings is.",
        "answer": "(c) Organizational behaviour",
        "options": [
            "(a) Individual behaviour",
            "(b) Group behaviour",
            "(c) Organizational behaviour",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 160,
        "question": "Following are the phases of the motivational process.",
        "answer": "(c) Both",
        "options": [
            "(a) Need identification",
            "(b) Selecting goals",
            "(c) Both",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 161,
        "question": "The 360-degree appraisal-",
        "answer": "(b) Provides feedback from a variety of individuals",
        "options": [
            "(a) Works best in large organizations",
            "(b) Provides feedback from a variety of individuals",
            "(c) Aids in developing competitive intelligence",
            "(d) Diminishes the effect of development in the appraisal process"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 162,
        "question": "Communication between two members of a project team from different functions but the same level of authority is communication.",
        "answer": "(c) Lateral",
        "options": [
            "(a) Upward",
            "(b) Downward",
            "(c) Lateral",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 163,
        "question": "Which of these suggestions is an effective way to deal with stress?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the given options",
        "options": [
            "(a) Meditation",
            "(b) Exercise",
            "(c) Talking with others",
            "(d) All of the given options"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 164,
        "question": "Which of the following is not correct for organizational behaviour?",
        "answer": "(d) None of these",
        "options": [
            "(a) Organizational behaviour is a disciplinary approach",
            "(b) Organizational behaviour helps in analysis of behaviour",
            "(c) Organizational behaviour is goal-oriented",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 165,
        "question": "Which of the following frameworks is based on the expectancy, demand, and incentive concepts?",
        "answer": "(a) The cognitive framework",
        "options": [
            "(a) The cognitive framework",
            "(b) The behaviouristic framework",
            "(c) The social learning framework",
            "(d) The supportive framework"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 166,
        "question": "Organizational behaviour is a field of study backed by a body of associated with growing concern for people at the workplace.",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Theory",
            "(b) Research",
            "(c) Application",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 167,
        "question": "The problem-solving process begins with.",
        "answer": "(c) Identification of the problem",
        "options": [
            "(a) Clarification of the situation",
            "(b) Establishment of options",
            "(c) Identification of the problem",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 168,
        "question": "leadership style is an expression of the leader's trust in The the abilities of his subordinates.",
        "answer": "(b) Delegative",
        "options": [
            "(a) Participative",
            "(b) Delegative",
            "(c) Authoritarian",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 169,
        "question": "Protection from discrimiovided to employking conditions and union formulation are.",
        "answer": "(c) Statutory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Contractual",
            "(b) Individual",
            "(c) Statutory",
            "(d) Organizational"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 170,
        "question": "We can define as activities people perform to acquire, enhance, and use power and other resources to obtain their preferred outcomes in a situation of uncertainty or disagreement.",
        "answer": "(a) Organizational politics",
        "options": [
            "(a) Organizational politics",
            "(b) Executing authority",
            "(c) Collective bargaining",
            "(d) Position power"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 171,
        "question": "Exists when individuals performing similar jobs for the same firm are paid according to factors unique to the employee.",
        "answer": "(c) Internal equity",
        "options": [
            "(a) Employee equity",
            "(b) Team equity",
            "(c) Internal equity",
            "(d) All of the given options"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 172,
        "question": "A system of retirement benefits that provides benefits like disability insurance, survivor's benefits, and medicare is called.",
        "answer": "(d) Social security benefit",
        "options": [
            "(a) Encoding",
            "(b) Unemployment compensation",
            "(c) Workers compensation",
            "(d) Social security benefit"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 173,
        "question": "Stress can affect not only your health but also other aspects of your life. What else can be affected by stress?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the given options",
        "options": [
            "(a) Family relationships",
            "(b) Work performance",
            "(c) Your attention to safety",
            "(d) All of the given options"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 174,
        "question": "\"Might is right\" is the motto of.",
        "answer": "(a) Autocratic model",
        "options": [
            "(a) Autocratic model",
            "(b) Custodial model",
            "(c) Supportive model",
            "(d) Collegial model"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 175,
        "question": "Which of the following frameworks is used in the development of the overall model of OB?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) The cognitive framework",
            "(b) The behaviouristic framework",
            "(c) The social learning framework",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 176,
        "question": "The study of organization behaviour has certain basic assumptions. They are:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) An industrial enterprise is an organization of people",
            "(b) These people must be motivated to work effectively",
            "(c) The goals of the employee and the employer may not necessarily coincide",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 177,
        "question": "Organizational behaviour is:",
        "answer": "(c) A science as well as an art",
        "options": [
            "(a) A science",
            "(b) An art",
            "(c) A science as well as an art",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 178,
        "question": "\"Leadership motivates the people to work and not power of money\". This concept is related to:",
        "answer": "(c) Supportive model",
        "options": [
            "(a) Autocratic model",
            "(b) Custodial model",
            "(c) Supportive model",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 179,
        "question": "In the present context, challenges for OB are:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Employee expectation",
            "(b) Workforce diversity",
            "(c) Globalization",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 180,
        "question": "Forces affecting organizational behaviour are:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) People",
            "(b) Environment",
            "(c) Technology",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 181,
        "question": "Embodies a team concept, is based on the principle of mutual contribution by employer and employees:",
        "answer": "(d) Collegial model",
        "options": [
            "(a) Autocratic model",
            "(b) Custodial model",
            "(c) Supportive model",
            "(d) Collegial model"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 182,
        "question": "Communication begins with:",
        "answer": "(d) Sender",
        "options": [
            "(a) Encoding",
            "(b) Decoding",
            "(c) Channel selection",
            "(d) Sender"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 183,
        "question": "A major problem with a task force type of management is:",
        "answer": "(c) Accountability",
        "options": [
            "(a) There is no logical basis for task force information",
            "(b) Its status is too inflexible",
            "(c) Accountability",
            "(d) Lack of planning"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 184,
        "question": "Organization structure primarily refers to:",
        "answer": "(a) How activities are coordinated & controlled",
        "options": [
            "(a) How activities are coordinated & controlled",
            "(b) How resources are allocated",
            "(c) The location of departments and office space",
            "(d) The policy statements developed by the firm"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 185,
        "question": "The philosophy that guides an organization' policies towards its employees and customers is an important part of:",
        "answer": "(c) Organizational culture",
        "options": [
            "(a) Management strategy",
            "(b) Organisation behaviour",
            "(c) Organizational culture",
            "(d) Oraganisation development"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 186,
        "question": "Anthropology is the science of mankind and the study of human behaviour as a whole:",
        "answer": "(a) True",
        "options": [
            "(a) True",
            "(b) False",
            "(c) Both",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 187,
        "question": "Diversity of organization behaviour can be in:",
        "answer": "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
        "options": [
            "(a) Cultural",
            "(b) Global",
            "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 188,
        "question": "Distance between two social systems known as:",
        "answer": "(d) None of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Cultural shock",
            "(b) Cultural change",
            "(c) Cultural contingencies",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 189,
        "question": "Which one of these is not the features of organizational behavior?",
        "answer": "(d) Software programme",
        "options": [
            "(a) Goal oriented",
            "(b) Human tool",
            "(c) Science and art",
            "(d) Software programme"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 190,
        "question": "Organizational behaviour helps in:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Effective use of human resource",
            "(b) Understand organization",
            "(c) Maintain Good organization culture",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 191,
        "question": "Autocratic model depend on:",
        "answer": "(c) Power",
        "options": [
            "(a) Rewards",
            "(b) Support",
            "(c) Power",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 192,
        "question": "Goals of organizations behaviour include:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Understand own behavior",
            "(b) Understand others behavio",
            "(c) Predicating and control of group behaviour",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 193,
        "question": "Herzberg's factor theory is associated with:",
        "answer": "(a) Motivation",
        "options": [
            "(a) Motivation",
            "(b) Communication",
            "(c) Salary",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 194,
        "question": "Which is not a sign of high morale and high productivity?",
        "answer": "(a) Lot of tension",
        "options": [
            "(a) Lot of tension",
            "(b) Confidence",
            "(c) Good work",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 195,
        "question": "The sources of accruing attitude are:",
        "answer": "(d) All of these",
        "options": [
            "(a) Family",
            "(b) Nabors hood",
            "(c) Association",
            "(d) All of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 196,
        "question": "What are the elements of personality?",
        "answer": "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
        "options": [
            "(a) Stable characteristic",
            "(b) Reputedly accruing",
            "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 197,
        "question": "It is the end state of feeling.",
        "answer": "(b) Job satisfaction",
        "options": [
            "(a) Job enrichment",
            "(b) Job satisfaction",
            "(c) Both",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 198,
        "question": "Turnover, productivity are the factors of job satisfaction:",
        "answer": "(c) Organization work environment",
        "options": [
            "(a) Personal characteristics",
            "(b) Work behaviour",
            "(c) Organization work environment",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 199,
        "question": "Perception process starts with:",
        "answer": "(b) Perceptual inputs",
        "options": [
            "(a) Conceptual output",
            "(b) Perceptual inputs",
            "(c) Work type",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 200,
        "question": "Internal factors affecting perception include:",
        "answer": "(d) None of these",
        "options": [
            "(a) Sensory limits",
            "(b) Psychological factors",
            "(c) Both",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 201,
        "question": "The four management functions include all of the following EXCEPT:",
        "answer": "(c) Staffing",
        "options": [
            "(a) Controlling",
            "(b) Planning",
            "(c) Staffing",
            "(d) Organizing"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 202,
        "question": "__________ means that organizations are becoming more heterogeneous in terms of gender, race, and ethnicity.",
        "answer": "(b) Workforce diversity",
        "options": [
            "(a) Globalization",
            "(b) Workforce diversity",
            "(c) Affirmative action",
            "(d) Organizational culture"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 203,
        "question": "All of the following topics and areas of concentration generally constitute OB except:",
        "answer": "(a) international influences",
        "options": [
            "(a) international influences",
            "(b) interpersonal communication",
            "(c) group structure and process",
            "(d) leadership"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 204,
        "question": "According to the OB model, all of the following are characteristics of human output except:",
        "answer": "(a) conflict",
        "options": [
            "(a) conflict",
            "(b) satisfaction",
            "(c) turnover",
            "(d) productivity"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 205,
        "question": "All of the following are advantages of diversity except:",
        "answer": "(d) increased cohesiveness",
        "options": [
            "(a) increased flexibility",
            "(b) increased creativity",
            "(c) multiple perspectives",
            "(d) increased cohesiveness"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 206,
        "question": "Teams are very useful in which of the following situations?",
        "answer": "(b) The tasks are interrelated",
        "options": [
            "(a) The work to be performed is very basic",
            "(b) The tasks are interrelated",
            "(c) No one wants to be accountable",
            "(d) The group is homogeneous"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 207,
        "question": "Quality Trilogy includes:",
        "answer": "(d) All the three",
        "options": [
            "(a) Quality planning",
            "(b) Quality improvement",
            "(c) Quality control",
            "(d) All the three"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 208,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a core topic of organizational behavior?",
        "answer": "(d) Resource allocation",
        "options": [
            "(a) Motivation",
            "(b) Attitude development",
            "(c) Conflict",
            "(d) Resource allocation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 209,
        "question": "A study of human behavior in organizational settings is:",
        "answer": "(c) organizational behavior",
        "options": [
            "(a) individual behavior",
            "(b) group behavior",
            "(c) organizational behavior",
            "(d) none of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 210,
        "question": "Today's organizations are:",
        "answer": "(a) open system",
        "options": [
            "(a) open system",
            "(b) closed system",
            "(c) open as well as closed",
            "(d) none of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 211,
        "question": "Forces affecting organizational behavior are:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) People",
            "(b) Environment",
            "(c) Technology",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 212,
        "question": "Which of the following forms the basis for the autocratic model of OB?",
        "answer": "(c) Power",
        "options": [
            "(a) Obedience",
            "(b) Authority",
            "(c) Power",
            "(d) Dependence on boss"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 213,
        "question": "Hawthorne experiment, which was a real beginning of applied research in OB, was conducted by:",
        "answer": "(a) Elton Mayo",
        "options": [
            "(a) Elton Mayo",
            "(b) Henry Fayol",
            "(c) F.W. Taylor",
            "(d) Max Weber"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 214,
        "question": "An OB study would be least likely to focus on which of the following problems?",
        "answer": "(c) a decrease in sales due to growing foreign competition",
        "options": [
            "(a) an increase in absenteeism at a certain company",
            "(b) a fall in productivity in one shift of a manufacturing plant",
            "(c) a decrease in sales due to growing foreign competition",
            "(d) an increase in theft by employees at a retail store"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 215,
        "question": "Which of the following OB topics is not central to managing employees' fears about terrorism?",
        "answer": "(d) Work Design",
        "options": [
            "(a) Emotion",
            "(b) Communication",
            "(c) Motivation",
            "(d) Work Design"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 216,
        "question": "OB is the __________",
        "answer": "(b) Human Behaviour",
        "options": [
            "(a) Human",
            "(b) Human Behaviour",
            "(c) Employer Human Behaviour",
            "(d) Employee Human Behaviour"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 217,
        "question": "Scope of OB does not include:",
        "answer": "(d) Technology",
        "options": [
            "(a) Leadership",
            "(b) Perception",
            "(c) Job design",
            "(d) Technology"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 218,
        "question": "Which is not a model of OB?",
        "answer": "(d) Behavioural model",
        "options": [
            "(a) Autocratic model",
            "(b) Custodial model",
            "(c) Supportive model",
            "(d) Behavioural model"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 219,
        "question": "Each of the independent at the diversified form illustrates:",
        "answer": "(c) Entrepreneurial form",
        "options": [
            "(a) Machine Bureaucracy",
            "(b) Processional Bureaucracy",
            "(c) Entrepreneurial form",
            "(d) Adhocracy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 220,
        "question": "OB does not contribute to improve:",
        "answer": "(d) Communication",
        "options": [
            "(a) Motivation",
            "(b) Efficiency",
            "(c) Interpersonal Relations",
            "(d) Communication"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 221,
        "question": "Extension of behaviour modification into organization is called:",
        "answer": "(b) OB Mod",
        "options": [
            "(a) Enrichment",
            "(b) OB Mod",
            "(c) Enlargement",
            "(d) OB Ext"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 222,
        "question": "Management skill is associated with:",
        "answer": "(d) All of these",
        "options": [
            "(a) Technical Skill",
            "(b) Human Skill",
            "(c) Conceptual Skill",
            "(d) All of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 223,
        "question": "Individual level independent variables include:",
        "answer": "(c) perception",
        "options": [
            "(a) technology",
            "(b) organizational culture",
            "(c) perception",
            "(d) human resource policy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 224,
        "question": "Which one of the following is NOT a factor that influences perception?",
        "answer": "(b) Medium",
        "options": [
            "(a) Target",
            "(b) Medium",
            "(c) Perceiver",
            "(d) Situation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 225,
        "question": "People in good moods use decisions or rules of thumb, to make:",
        "answer": "(c) heuristics",
        "options": [
            "(a) Self-management",
            "(b) theories",
            "(c) heuristics",
            "(d) empathy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 226,
        "question": "Changing a worker's attitude is not an easy task. To get a worker to change their attitude requires a variety of approaches which can include all of the following except:",
        "answer": "(b) clearly telling the individual what is expected.",
        "options": [
            "(a) presenting strong evidence to support your reasons for wanting an attitude change",
            "(b) clearly telling the individual what is expected.",
            "(c) presenting arguments which fit each individual being targeted for change",
            "(d) appealing to the individual's fears, frustrations and other emotions."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 227,
        "question": "Which of Maslow's needs best approximates McClelland's need for achievement?",
        "answer": "(a) Esteem",
        "options": [
            "(a) Esteem",
            "(b) Self-actualization",
            "(c) Physiological",
            "(d) Social"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 228,
        "question": "What are the three key elements of motivation?",
        "answer": "(d) Intensity, direction and persistence",
        "options": [
            "(a) Interest, activity and reward",
            "(b) Awareness, effort and outcome",
            "(c) Stimulation, progress and achievement",
            "(d) Intensity, direction and persistence"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 229,
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT included in the values across cultures?",
        "answer": "(c) Assertiveness",
        "options": [
            "(a) Uncertainty Avoidance",
            "(b) Power Distance",
            "(c) Assertiveness",
            "(d) Individualism versus collectivism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 230,
        "question": "According to Maslow, when does a need stop motivating?",
        "answer": "(a) When it is substantially satisfied",
        "options": [
            "(a) When it is substantially satisfied",
            "(b) It never stops motivating",
            "(c) When one returns to a lower level need",
            "(d) When one chooses to move to a higher level need"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 231,
        "question": "Who has given the hierarchy of needs theory of motivation?",
        "answer": "(a) Abraham Maslow",
        "options": [
            "(a) Abraham Maslow",
            "(b) David McClelland",
            "(c) Victor Vroom",
            "(d) Frederick Herzberg"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 232,
        "question": "How many levels are there in Needs Hierarchy theory of motivation?",
        "answer": "(b) 5",
        "options": [
            "(a) 6",
            "(b) 5",
            "(c) 4",
            "(d) 3"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 233,
        "question": "A person has two important attitudes. Those attitudes are likely to be:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Mutually consistent",
            "(b) Accessible",
            "(c) Persistent over time",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 234,
        "question": "Talkative vs. silent: frank, open vs. secretive: adventurous vs. cautious; sociable vs. reclusive these traits describe which dimension of personality?",
        "answer": "(c) Extraversion",
        "options": [
            "(a) Agreeableness",
            "(b) Conscientiousness",
            "(c) Extraversion",
            "(d) Culture"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 235,
        "question": "An early science that tried to correlate personality with measurements of parts of the skull is known as:",
        "answer": "(a) phrenology",
        "options": [
            "(a) phrenology",
            "(b) psychology",
            "(c) physiology",
            "(d) personality psychology"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 236,
        "question": "The id operates on the __________ principle.",
        "answer": "(b) pleasure",
        "options": [
            "(a) reality",
            "(b) pleasure",
            "(c) instant gratification",
            "(d) guilt"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 237,
        "question": "A personality assessment where a person responds to ambiguous stimuli, revealing unconscious feelings, impulses, and desires is:",
        "answer": "(b) projective test",
        "options": [
            "(a) self-report inventory",
            "(b) projective test",
            "(c) Minnesota Multiphasic Personality Inventory (MMPI)",
            "(d) Myers-Briggs Type Indicator (MBTI)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 238,
        "question": "The way a person reacts to the world, starting when they are very young, including the person's activity level is known as:",
        "answer": "(b) temperament",
        "options": [
            "(a) traits",
            "(b) temperament",
            "(c) heritability",
            "(d) personality"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 239,
        "question": "Temperament refers to:",
        "answer": "(a) inborn, genetically based personality differences",
        "options": [
            "(a) inborn, genetically based personality differences",
            "(b) characteristic ways of behaving",
            "(c) conscientiousness, agreeableness, neuroticism, openness and extroversion",
            "(d) degree of introversion-extroversion"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 240,
        "question": "A(n) __________ is a situation in which an employee must define right and wrong conduct.",
        "answer": "(b) ethical dilemma",
        "options": [
            "(a) problem",
            "(b) ethical dilemma",
            "(c) argument",
            "(d) principle"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 241,
        "question": "According to the Myers-Briggs Type Indicator, people who are classified as __________ are conceptualizers.",
        "answer": "(c) ENTPs",
        "options": [
            "(a) INTJs",
            "(b) ESTJs",
            "(c) ENTPs",
            "(d) MBTIs"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 242,
        "question": "If somebody is described as having a 'Type A' personality, which of the following behaviors would you be least likely to witness?",
        "answer": "(d) laid-back interpersonal style",
        "options": [
            "(a) doing things rapidly (eating, walking, speaking)",
            "(b) impatience",
            "(c) preoccupation with measuring things",
            "(d) laid-back interpersonal style"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 243,
        "question": "An individual's personality is determined by:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Heredity",
            "(b) Environment",
            "(c) Situational factors",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 244,
        "question": "'Cognitive theory' of learning was given by:",
        "answer": "(d) Piajet",
        "options": [
            "(a) Skinner",
            "(b) Pavlov",
            "(c) Tolman",
            "(d) Piajet"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 245,
        "question": "Thematic Apperception Test (TAT) is designed to understand:",
        "answer": "(c) Personality of individual",
        "options": [
            "(a) Perception of individual",
            "(b) Learning of individual",
            "(c) Personality of individual",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 246,
        "question": "What do we call it when we judge someone on the basis of our perception?",
        "answer": "(a) Stereotyping",
        "options": [
            "(a) Stereotyping",
            "(b) Categorizing",
            "(c) Halo effect",
            "(d) Prototyping"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 247,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a trait dimension in Big 5 personality trait?",
        "answer": "(c) Ego",
        "options": [
            "(a) Extroversion",
            "(b) Agreeableness",
            "(c) Ego",
            "(d) Culture"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 248,
        "question": "If everyone who is faced with a similar situation responds in the same way, attribution theory states that the behavior shows:",
        "answer": "(a) Consensus",
        "options": [
            "(a) Consensus",
            "(b) Similarity",
            "(c) Reliability",
            "(d) Consistency"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 249,
        "question": "Four processes have been found to determine the influence that a model will have on an individual. Which of the following is not one of those processes?",
        "answer": "(d) consequential processes",
        "options": [
            "(a) attention processes",
            "(b) retention processes",
            "(c) motor reproduction processes",
            "(d) consequential processes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 250,
        "question": "'Person-Job fit' means:",
        "answer": "(b) Persons skills match with the job",
        "options": [
            "(a) Persons physical fitness match with the job",
            "(b) Persons skills match with the job",
            "(c) Persons contributions match with the incentives offered by the organization",
            "(d) Persons education match with the job"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 251,
        "question": "Dependable, responsible are part of Big 5 personality trait as:",
        "answer": "(b) Conscientious",
        "options": [
            "(a) Emotional Stability",
            "(b) Conscientious",
            "(c) Openness to experience",
            "(d) Introversion"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 252,
        "question": "Relaxed and Secure are part of Big 5 personality trait as:",
        "answer": "(d) Emotional Stability",
        "options": [
            "(a) Agreeableness",
            "(b) Openness to experience",
            "(c) Introversion",
            "(d) Emotional Stability"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 253,
        "question": "Myers-Briggs Personality is called as:",
        "answer": "(c) MBTI",
        "options": [
            "(a) MBIT",
            "(b) MBET",
            "(c) MBTI",
            "(d) MIBT"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 254,
        "question": "MBTI tests the personalities in how many categories?",
        "answer": "(b) 4",
        "options": [
            "(a) 3",
            "(b) 4",
            "(c) 5",
            "(d) 6"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 255,
        "question": "MBTI stands for:",
        "answer": "(c) Myers-Briggs Type Indicator",
        "options": [
            "(a) Myers-Briggs Test Indicator",
            "(b) Myers-Briggs Test Investigator",
            "(c) Myers-Briggs Type Indicator",
            "(d) Myers-Briggs Type Investigator"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 256,
        "question": "The psychoanalytic theory of personality is primarily developed by:",
        "answer": "(b) Sigmund Freud",
        "options": [
            "(a) Carl Jung",
            "(b) Sigmund Freud",
            "(c) Alfred Adler",
            "(d) G. W. Allport"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 257,
        "question": "__________ is our perception of one personality trait influencing how we view a person's entire personality.",
        "answer": "(b) Halo effect",
        "options": [
            "(a) Perception",
            "(b) Halo effect",
            "(c) Stereotyping",
            "(d) Individual Personality"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 258,
        "question": "What aspect(s) of personality are believed to have evolved in humans?",
        "answer": "(d) all of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) overeating",
            "(b) quick response to danger",
            "(c) aggression in men",
            "(d) all of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 259,
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the stages of psychosocial development according to Erikson?",
        "answer": "(d) life vs. death",
        "options": [
            "(a) Industry vs. Inferiority",
            "(b) Intimacy vs. Isolation",
            "(c) Trust vs. Mistrust",
            "(d) Life vs. Death"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 260,
        "question": "An individual exploring different options while making a decision is in:",
        "answer": "(c) moratorium",
        "options": [
            "(a) identity diffusion",
            "(b) identity foreclosure",
            "(c) moratorium",
            "(d) negative identity"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 261,
        "question": "The following are examples of negative stressors:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Unemployment",
            "(b) Legal problems",
            "(c) Divorce",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 262,
        "question": "Anxiety can cause the following moods:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Irritable",
            "(b) Nervous",
            "(c) Panicky",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 263,
        "question": "What thoughts come to the mind when you're under negative stress?",
        "answer": "(b) You think that you cannot cope with the situation",
        "options": [
            "(a) You think that you can cope with the situation",
            "(b) You think that you cannot cope with the situation",
            "(c) You think that everything will get fine eventually",
            "(d) You think that you will get help immediately"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 264,
        "question": "Aches, shallow breathing and sweating, frequent colds are:",
        "answer": "(a) Physical symptoms of stress",
        "options": [
            "(a) Physical symptoms of stress",
            "(b) Behavioural symptoms of stress",
            "(c) Emotional symptoms of stress",
            "(d) Cognitive symptoms of stress"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 265,
        "question": "The following are examples of positive stressors:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) New job",
            "(b) Having a child",
            "(c) Buying a home",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 266,
        "question": "Who was the first to describe the 'fight or flight response'?",
        "answer": "(a) Walter B. Cannon",
        "options": [
            "(a) Walter B. Cannon",
            "(b) Sigmund Freud",
            "(c) Atkinson Potter",
            "(d) Mrunal Sengupta"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 267,
        "question": "Which of the following are true in relation to Relaxation Response?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) It is a physical state of deep rest",
            "(b) Eliciting this reduces your metabolism",
            "(c) Eliciting this reduces your blood pressure",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 268,
        "question": "Which of the following is true about 'deep breathing relaxation'?",
        "answer": "(d) Only 'a' & 'b' are true",
        "options": [
            "(a) It helps slow the heartbeat and lower blood pressure",
            "(b) It releases tension from the body and clears your mind",
            "(c) You have to do this under-water",
            "(d) Only 'a' & 'b' are true"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 269,
        "question": "Which of the following are true about the 'Guided Imagery technique'?",
        "answer": "(a) It is like vivid daydreaming",
        "options": [
            "(a) It is like vivid daydreaming",
            "(b) You need a hypnotist for this technique",
            "(c) You need to rest in a sleeping posture",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 270,
        "question": "Stress management is about learning:",
        "answer": "(b) How to develop skills that would enhance our body's adjustment when we are subjected to the pressures of life",
        "options": [
            "(a) How to avoid the pressures of life",
            "(b) How to develop skills that would enhance our body's adjustment when we are subjected to the pressures of life",
            "(c) Both '1' & '2' are true",
            "(d) None of the these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 271,
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true?",
        "answer": "(b) Moodiness is an emotional symptom of stress",
        "options": [
            "(a) Moodiness is a cognitive symptom of stress",
            "(b) Moodiness is an emotional symptom of stress",
            "(c) Poor judgment is an emotional symptom of stress",
            "(d) Agitation is a cognitive symptom of stress"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 272,
        "question": "The following are true about the behavioral symptoms of stress:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) The subject starts eating more or less",
            "(b) The subject starts sleeping more or less",
            "(c) The subject isolates himself/herself from others",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 273,
        "question": "All of the following statements pertaining to stress are true except:",
        "answer": "(d) Individual factors do not affect stress in the workplace.",
        "options": [
            "(a) Stress can improve employee performance.",
            "(b) Stress is additive in nature.",
            "(c) People react differently to stress situations.",
            "(d) Individual factors do not affect stress in the workplace."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 274,
        "question": "Which of the following was not identified as an individual variable moderating the relationship between potential stressors and experienced stress?",
        "answer": "(c) Social support",
        "options": [
            "(a) Achievement need",
            "(b) Locus of control",
            "(c) Social support",
            "(d) Job satisfaction"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 275,
        "question": "Organizationally supported programs that focus on the employee's total physical and mental condition are called:",
        "answer": "(b) wellness programs",
        "options": [
            "(a) Job redesign programs",
            "(b) Wellness programs",
            "(c) Employee involvement programs",
            "(d) Organizational development programs"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 276,
        "question": "Stress can affect not only your health but also other aspects of your life. What else can be affected by stress?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the given options",
        "options": [
            "(a) Family relationships",
            "(b) Work performance",
            "(c) Your attention to safety",
            "(d) All of the given options"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 277,
        "question": "Which of the following is/are not a method of managing stress?",
        "answer": "(d) Rorschach test",
        "options": [
            "(a) Time management",
            "(b) Supervisor training",
            "(c) Role Analysis techniques (RAT)",
            "(d) Rorschach test"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 278,
        "question": "According to the Canadian government, stress has _______ costs.",
        "answer": "(d) all of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) social",
            "(b) economic",
            "(c) personal",
            "(d) all of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 279,
        "question": "Commitment, control, and challenge are all elements of:",
        "answer": "(c) hardiness",
        "options": [
            "(a) tardiness",
            "(b) stress",
            "(c) hardiness",
            "(d) depression"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 280,
        "question": "Which stress hormone increases heart rate and elevates blood pressure?",
        "answer": "(c) adrenaline",
        "options": [
            "(a) cortisol",
            "(b) progesterone",
            "(c) adrenaline",
            "(d) dopamine"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 281,
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT associated with workplace stress?",
        "answer": "(c) supervisory support",
        "options": [
            "(a) work overload",
            "(b) job insecurity",
            "(c) supervisory support",
            "(d) conflict with co-workers"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 282,
        "question": "Groups are defined by the organization's structure:",
        "answer": "(b) Formal",
        "options": [
            "(a) Informal",
            "(b) Formal",
            "(c) Friendship",
            "(d) Interest"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 283,
        "question": "QFD stands for:",
        "answer": "(c) Quality function deployment",
        "options": [
            "(a) Quantity for deployment",
            "(b) Quality for deployment",
            "(c) Quality function deployment",
            "(d) Quality for decision"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 284,
        "question": "Which of the following skills is required for an effective team?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Problem-solving skills",
            "(b) Technical expertise",
            "(c) Interpersonal skills",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 285,
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true concerning the climate of trust?",
        "answer": "(b) Interpersonal trust among team members reduces the need to monitor each other's behaviour.",
        "options": [
            "(a) Interpersonal trust among team members inhibits cooperation.",
            "(b) Interpersonal trust among team members reduces the need to monitor each other's behaviour.",
            "(c) Interpersonal trust among team members bonds members with the belief that others will take advice from them if given the opportunity.",
            "(d) Interpersonal trust among team members increases members' aversion to risk."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 286,
        "question": "Which of the following is / are not direct methods to solve intergroup conflicts?",
        "answer": "(d) Persuasion",
        "options": [
            "(a) Problem solving",
            "(b) Domination by the management",
            "(c) Removing key figures in conflict",
            "(d) Persuasion"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 287,
        "question": "Which of the following statements is TRUE?",
        "answer": "(b) All managers are not leaders.",
        "options": [
            "(a) All leaders are managers.",
            "(b) All managers are not leaders.",
            "(c) The formal rights associated with management provide assurance that managers can lead effectively.",
            "(d) Non-sanctioned leadership is not as important as formal influence."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 288,
        "question": "Leaders who know who they are, know what they believe in and value, and act on those values and beliefs openly and candidly are called:",
        "answer": "(d) Authentic",
        "options": [
            "(a) Transformational",
            "(b) Transactional",
            "(c) Charismatic",
            "(d) Authentic"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 289,
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a substitute for leadership?",
        "answer": "(b) Rigid rules and procedures",
        "options": [
            "(a) Explicit formalized goals",
            "(b) Rigid rules and procedures",
            "(c) Cohesive work groups",
            "(d) Professional orientation of employees"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 290,
        "question": "Which one of the following characteristics is not part of the definition of a group?",
        "answer": "(c) organizationally assigned goals",
        "options": [
            "(a) Interdependent",
            "(b) Two or more members",
            "(c) Organizationally assigned goals",
            "(d) Interacting"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 291,
        "question": "Work groups of employees and supervisors that meet regularly to discuss their quality problems and recommend solutions is a form of participative management called:",
        "answer": "(d) Quality circles",
        "options": [
            "(a) Department teams",
            "(b) Cooperative groups",
            "(c) Evaluation teams",
            "(d) Quality circles"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 292,
        "question": "Which of the following is detrimental to group cohesiveness?",
        "answer": "(a) Diversity",
        "options": [
            "(a) Diversity",
            "(b) Education",
            "(c) Teamwork",
            "(d) Trust"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 293,
        "question": "Continued membership in a group will usually require:",
        "answer": "(b) Conforming to group norms",
        "options": [
            "(a) Supporting the group leader",
            "(b) Conforming to group norms",
            "(c) Encouraging cohesiveness in the group",
            "(d) Developing a status system"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 294,
        "question": "Concerning leadership concepts, which statement is true?",
        "answer": "(b) It is likely that a particular set of leader characteristics and behaviors do suit specific situations and groups.",
        "options": [
            "(a) Leader roles are unnecessary in organizations like Gore-Tex, where a self-leadership approach is used.",
            "(b) It is likely that a particular set of leader characteristics and behaviors do suit specific situations and groups.",
            "(c) It is likely that the need for leaders will decline in the 21st century due to more decentralized structures.",
            "(d) The military model of leadership will become more popular in the 21st century."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 295,
        "question": "Which of the following types of power requires acceptance of the leader's authority by members of the organization?",
        "answer": "(c) Legitimate",
        "options": [
            "(a) Personal",
            "(b) Organizational",
            "(c) Legitimate",
            "(d) Positional"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 296,
        "question": "Which of the following best describes a leader?",
        "answer": "(d) Leaders influence others beyond the formal authority",
        "options": [
            "(a) Being a leader also means being a manager",
            "(b) Leaders can emerge from within a group",
            "(c) Leaders are appointed to their positions",
            "(d) Leaders influence others beyond the formal authority"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 297,
        "question": "Which of the following is one of the drawbacks of group decision making?",
        "answer": "(b) More amount of time is required to make a decision",
        "options": [
            "(a) More knowledge through pooling of group resources",
            "(b) More amount of time is required to make a decision",
            "(c) Increased acceptance & commitment due to voice in decisions",
            "(d) Greater understanding due to involvement in decision stages"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 298,
        "question": "Which of the following statement is TRUE regarding trait theories?",
        "answer": "(c) Suggest leaders are born and not made",
        "options": [
            "(a) Fit traits to various situations",
            "(b) Emphasize the situation in classifying approaches to leadership",
            "(c) Suggest leaders are born and not made",
            "(d) Focus on leaders' physical attributes, personality, and abilities"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 299,
        "question": "Free rein leadership is also known as:",
        "answer": "(c) Laissez-faire",
        "options": [
            "(a) Democratic",
            "(b) Autocratic",
            "(c) Laissez-faire",
            "(d) Bureaucratic"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 300,
        "question": "_________ leadership emphasizes on rules and regulations in an organization.",
        "answer": "(d) Bureaucratic",
        "options": [
            "(a) Democratic",
            "(b) Autocratic",
            "(c) Laissez-faire",
            "(d) Bureaucratic"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 301,
        "question": "Communication begins with",
        "answer": "(b) idea origination",
        "options": [
            "(a) encoding",
            "(b) idea origination",
            "(c) decoding",
            "(d) channel selection"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 302,
        "question": "A study of the culture and practices in different societies is called",
        "answer": "(b) Anthropology",
        "options": [
            "(a) Personality",
            "(b) Anthropology",
            "(c) Perception",
            "(d) Attitudes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 303,
        "question": "Scope of Organizational Behaviour does not include",
        "answer": "(d) Technology",
        "options": [
            "(a) Leadership",
            "(b) Perception",
            "(c) Job Design",
            "(d) Technology"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 304,
        "question": "In present context, challenges for Organizational Behaviour are",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Employee expectation",
            "(b) Workforce diversity",
            "(c) Globalization",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 305,
        "question": "Meso organisation behaviour is related with",
        "answer": "(b) Group behaviour",
        "options": [
            "(a) Individual behaviour",
            "(b) Group behaviour",
            "(c) Organisational behaviour",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 306,
        "question": "Organizational behaviour focuses at 3 Levels:",
        "answer": "(d) Individual, Groups, Organisation.",
        "options": [
            "(a) Individuals, Organisation, Society",
            "(b) Society, Organisation, Nation",
            "(c) Employee, Employer, Management",
            "(d) Individual, Groups, Organisation."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 307,
        "question": "________ is recognised as father of 'Human relations'",
        "answer": "(d) Elton Mayo",
        "options": [
            "(a) William Gilbreth",
            "(b) Hendry Fayol",
            "(c) F.W. Taylor",
            "(d) Elton Mayo"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 308,
        "question": "Some of OB's challenges and opportunities include all of the following except:",
        "answer": "(a) reinforcing the importance of traditional methods of management",
        "options": [
            "(a) reinforcing the importance of traditional methods of management",
            "(b) offering specific insights to improve interpersonal and people skills",
            "(c) helping us learn to cope with the continuous changing world",
            "(d) facilitating the improvement of quality and employee productivity"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 309,
        "question": "Edward Tolman is related to",
        "answer": "(b) Cognitive approach",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behaviourist Framework",
            "(b) Cognitive approach",
            "(c) Social Cognitive Framework",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 310,
        "question": "Hawthorne Studies is related to which stage of the organisational behaviour evolution?",
        "answer": "(d) Human relations movement",
        "options": [
            "(a) Industrial revolution",
            "(b) Scientific management",
            "(c) Organisational behaviour",
            "(d) Human relations movement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 311,
        "question": "Which of the following represents the correct sequencing of historical developments of Organisational Behaviour?",
        "answer": "(a) Industrial revolution -> Scientific management -> Human relations movement -> OB",
        "options": [
            "(a) Industrial revolution -> Scientific management -> Human relations movement -> OB",
            "(b) Industrial revolution -> Scientific management -> OB -> Human relations movement",
            "(c) Scientific management -> Human relations movement -> Industrial revolution -> OB",
            "(d) None of these."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 312,
        "question": "The field of organizational behaviour examines such questions as the nature of leadership, effective team development, and:",
        "answer": "(a) Interpersonal conflict resolution; motivation of individuals",
        "options": [
            "(a) Interpersonal conflict resolution; motivation of individuals",
            "(b) Organisational control; conflict management",
            "(c) Motivation of individuals; planning",
            "(d) Planning; development"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 313,
        "question": "Organisational Behaviour is a field of study backed by:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Theory",
            "(b) Research",
            "(c) Application",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 314,
        "question": "Which of the following is not correct for the organisational behaviour?",
        "answer": "(b) Organisational behaviour is a disciplinary approach.",
        "options": [
            "(a) Organisational behaviour is an integral part of management",
            "(b) Organisational behaviour is a disciplinary approach.",
            "(c) Organisational behaviour helps in analysis of behaviour",
            "(d) Organisational behaviour is goal-oriented"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 315,
        "question": "Which one of the following is the definition given by Fred Luthans?",
        "answer": "(a) Organisational behaviour is to understand, predicting and controlling human behaviour at work",
        "options": [
            "(a) Organisational behaviour is to understand, predicting and controlling human behaviour at work",
            "(b) Organisational behaviour is subset of management activities concerned with human behaviour",
            "(c) Organisational behaviour is a branch of social sciences that seeks to build theories",
            "(d) Organisational behaviour is a field of study that investigates the impact on behaviour"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 316,
        "question": "Contribution/s of human relations movement is/are",
        "answer": "(d) All of these",
        "options": [
            "(a) Great Depression",
            "(b) Labour Movement",
            "(c) Hawthorne Studies",
            "(d) All of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 317,
        "question": "Nowadays a lot of stress is being put on the employee in the organisation on the",
        "answer": "(c) Behaviour",
        "options": [
            "(a) Character",
            "(b) Improvement",
            "(c) Behaviour",
            "(d) Rewards"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 318,
        "question": "The term 'psychology' is derived from the word psyche, which means 'soul' or 'spirit' in",
        "answer": "(c) Greek",
        "options": [
            "(a) Latin",
            "(b) French",
            "(c) Greek",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 319,
        "question": "The field of organisational behaviour is primarily concerned with:",
        "answer": "(d) Both a and c.",
        "options": [
            "(a) The behaviour of individual and groups.",
            "(b) How resources are effectively managed",
            "(c) Control processes and interactions between organisations and external context.",
            "(d) Both a and c."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 320,
        "question": "The __________ is based on the environment. Though cognitive processes like thinking, expectations and perception do exist, they are not needed to manage or predict behaviour.",
        "answer": "(a) Behaviouristic approach, Cognitive processes",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behaviouristic approach, Cognitive processes",
            "(b) Cognitive processes, Behaviouristic approach",
            "(c) Social cognitive, Behaviouristic approach",
            "(d) Cognitive processes, Social cognitive"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 321,
        "question": "Organisational Behaviour is the study of ________ in an organisation",
        "answer": "(c) Human Behaviour",
        "options": [
            "(a) Human",
            "(b) Employer",
            "(c) Human Behaviour",
            "(d) Employees"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 322,
        "question": "The model(s) of organisational behaviour is (are):",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Autocratic",
            "(b) Supportive",
            "(c) Custodial",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 323,
        "question": "OB helps to understand behaviour of humans in",
        "answer": "(b) Work place only",
        "options": [
            "(a) Work place and Society",
            "(b) Work place only",
            "(c) Society only",
            "(d) Department only"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 324,
        "question": "In present context, challenges for OB are:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Employee expectation",
            "(b) Workforce diversity",
            "(c) Globalization",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 325,
        "question": "Due to emphasis on productivity & efficiency, employees are not allowed to work with harmony with one another. This is a limitation of",
        "answer": "(c) Organizational Behaviour",
        "options": [
            "(a) Organizational Culture",
            "(b) Organizational Structure",
            "(c) Organizational Behaviour",
            "(d) Organisational Value"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 326,
        "question": "Common uniform, canteen, office does not mean common treatment is a limitation of",
        "answer": "(c) Organizational Behaviour",
        "options": [
            "(a) Organizational Culture",
            "(b) Organizational Structure",
            "(c) Organizational Behaviour",
            "(d) Organisational Value"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 327,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a contributing discipline of OB?",
        "answer": "(c) Physiology",
        "options": [
            "(a) Anthropology",
            "(b) Psychology",
            "(c) Physiology",
            "(d) Sociology"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 328,
        "question": "________ is a study of individual behaviour",
        "answer": "(b) Psychology",
        "options": [
            "(a) Anthropology",
            "(b) Psychology",
            "(c) Political science",
            "(d) Sociology"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 329,
        "question": "________ is a study of group behaviour",
        "answer": "(d) Sociology",
        "options": [
            "(a) Anthropology",
            "(b) Psychology",
            "(c) Physiology",
            "(d) Sociology"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 330,
        "question": "________ focuses on man, his work, and culture.",
        "answer": "(a) Anthropology",
        "options": [
            "(a) Anthropology",
            "(b) Psychology",
            "(c) Social psychology",
            "(d) Sociology"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 331,
        "question": "________ focuses on the influence of people on one another.",
        "answer": "(c) Social psychology",
        "options": [
            "(a) Anthropology",
            "(b) Psychology",
            "(c) Social psychology",
            "(d) Sociology"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 332,
        "question": "________ framework is based on the concept of Expectancy, demand, and intention of the human being.",
        "answer": "(c) Cognitive",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behaviouristic",
            "(b) Expectancy",
            "(c) Cognitive",
            "(d) Social learning"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 333,
        "question": "The study of organizational behaviour has certain basic assumptions. They are:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above.",
        "options": [
            "(a) An industrial enterprise is an organisation of people.",
            "(b) These people must be motivated to work effectively.",
            "(c) The goals of the employee and the employer may not necessarily coincide.",
            "(d) All of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 334,
        "question": "'Leadership motivates the people to work and not the power of money', this concept is related to:",
        "answer": "(c) Supportive Model",
        "options": [
            "(a) Autocratic model",
            "(b) Custodial model",
            "(c) Supportive Model",
            "(d) Collegial Model"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 335,
        "question": "The study of organization behavior has certain basic assumptions. They are:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) An industrial enterprise is an organization of people.",
            "(b) These people must be motivated to work effectively.",
            "(c) The goals of the employee and the employer may not necessarily coincide.",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 336,
        "question": "Which of the following frameworks is used in the development of the overall model of OB?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) The cognitive framework",
            "(b) The behaviouristic framework",
            "(c) The social learning framework",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 337,
        "question": "Which of the following frameworks is based on the expectancy, demand, and incentive concepts?",
        "answer": "(a) The cognitive framework",
        "options": [
            "(a) The cognitive framework",
            "(b) The behaviouristic framework",
            "(c) The social learning framework",
            "(d) The supportive framework"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 338,
        "question": "According to Edward Tolman, ________ consists of the expectancy that a particular event will lead to a particular consequence.",
        "answer": "(c) Learning",
        "options": [
            "(a) Eventual",
            "(b) Behaviour",
            "(c) Learning",
            "(d) Attitude"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 339,
        "question": "The 3 Theoretical Frameworks of OB are:",
        "answer": "(b) Cognitive, Behaviouristic, Social",
        "options": [
            "(a) Cognitive, Social, Technical",
            "(b) Cognitive, Behaviouristic, Social",
            "(c) Leadership, Attribution, Motivation",
            "(d) Attribution, Perception, and Motivation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 340,
        "question": "________ explains internal processes of choice among different behaviors.",
        "answer": "(b) Expectancy theory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Equity Theory",
            "(b) Expectancy theory",
            "(c) Goal attainment theory",
            "(d) Goal setting Theory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 341,
        "question": "________ explains how and why people react when they are unfairly treated.",
        "answer": "(a) Equity Theory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Equity Theory",
            "(b) Expectancy theory",
            "(c) Goal attainment theory",
            "(d) Goal setting Theory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 342,
        "question": "________ focuses on how to set goals for people to reach.",
        "answer": "(d) Goal setting Theory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Equity Theory",
            "(b) Expectancy theory",
            "(c) Goal attainment theory",
            "(d) Goal setting Theory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 343,
        "question": "Every individual sets his goal and he also knows the ________ will take him to achieve the goal.",
        "answer": "(b) Behaviour",
        "options": [
            "(a) Process",
            "(b) Behaviour",
            "(c) Event",
            "(d) Way"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 344,
        "question": "________ insist that it is advisable and fruitful to study the behavior of the human being which is visible than studying that which is elusive in nature.",
        "answer": "(a) Ivan Pavlov and Jon B. Watson",
        "options": [
            "(a) Ivan Pavlov and Jon B. Watson",
            "(b) Ivan Pavlov",
            "(c) Jon B. Watson",
            "(d) Ivan Pavlov and A. Maslow"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 345,
        "question": "________ is the behaviour for a stimulus.",
        "answer": "(b) Response",
        "options": [
            "(a) Stimulus",
            "(b) Response",
            "(c) Perception",
            "(d) Attitude"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 346,
        "question": "________ behavioural framework is based on behaviour and environmental variables.",
        "answer": "(b) Observable - Observable",
        "options": [
            "(a) Observable - Non Observable",
            "(b) Observable - Observable",
            "(c) Non Observable - Observable",
            "(d) Non Observable - Non Observable"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 347,
        "question": "Human behaviour can project ________ behaviour for a stimulus and exhibit a ________ response depending on environmental consequences.",
        "answer": "(d) different, same",
        "options": [
            "(a) different, different",
            "(b) same, same",
            "(c) same, different",
            "(d) different, same"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 348,
        "question": "As per ________, behaviour is not the outcome of stimulus alone, but it is an outcome which also depends on contingent environmental consequences of a behaviour.",
        "answer": "(a) Behaviouristic Framework",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behaviouristic Framework",
            "(b) Cognitive Framework",
            "(c) Skinner Framework",
            "(d) Behaviour Theory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 349,
        "question": "________ means the mental action or process of acquiring knowledge and understanding through thought, experience, and the senses.",
        "answer": "(c) Cognition",
        "options": [
            "(a) Learning",
            "(b) Development",
            "(c) Cognition",
            "(d) Training"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 350,
        "question": "The social cognitive theory states that the person and the external situations are ________ with each other along with the behaviour itself to determine the behaviour.",
        "answer": "(c) Interdependence",
        "options": [
            "(a) Related",
            "(b) Linked",
            "(c) Interdependence",
            "(d) Combined"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 351,
        "question": "________ states that along with cognitive and external situation the experiences faced through relevant past events determines what a person becomes and this will create an impact in subsequent behaviour.",
        "answer": "(c) Social Cognitive Framework",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behaviouristic Framework",
            "(b) Cognitive Framework",
            "(c) Social Cognitive Framework",
            "(d) Social Framework"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 352,
        "question": "________ developed social learning theory into the more comprehensive social cognitive theory (SCT).",
        "answer": "(a) Bandura",
        "options": [
            "(a) Bandura",
            "(b) Luthans",
            "(c) Skinner",
            "(d) I. Pavlov"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 353,
        "question": "________ have translated this SCT into the theoretical framework for organizational behavior.",
        "answer": "(a) Stajkovic and Luthans",
        "options": [
            "(a) Stajkovic and Luthans",
            "(b) Stajkovic and Skinner",
            "(c) Skinner and Luthans",
            "(d) Stajkovic and Pavlov"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 354,
        "question": "Bandura identified basic human capabilities as a part of SCT. How many did he identify?",
        "answer": "(c) 5",
        "options": [
            "(a) 3",
            "(b) 4",
            "(c) 5",
            "(d) 6"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 355,
        "question": "People process visual experiences into cognitive models. They help in future action. This is known as:",
        "answer": "(a) Symbolizing",
        "options": [
            "(a) Symbolizing",
            "(b) Forethought",
            "(c) Observational",
            "(d) Regulatory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 356,
        "question": "Employees plan their actions. This is called:",
        "answer": "(b) Forethought",
        "options": [
            "(a) Symbolizing",
            "(b) Forethought",
            "(c) Observational",
            "(d) Self-regulatory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 357,
        "question": "Employees learn by observing the performance of the referent group (peers, supervisors, and high performers) and the consequences of their actions. This is referred to as:",
        "answer": "(c) Observational",
        "options": [
            "(a) Symbolizing",
            "(b) Forethought",
            "(c) Observational",
            "(d) Self-regulatory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 358,
        "question": "Employees self-regulate their actions by setting internal standards. This is known as:",
        "answer": "(d) Self-regulatory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Self-reflective",
            "(b) Forethought",
            "(c) Observational",
            "(d) Self-regulatory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 359,
        "question": "Employees reflect back on their actions (how did I do?) and perceptually determine how they believe they can successfully accomplish the task in the future given the context. This is called:",
        "answer": "(a) Self-reflective",
        "options": [
            "(a) Self-reflective",
            "(b) Forethought",
            "(c) Observational",
            "(d) Self-regulatory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 360,
        "question": "Expectancy theory is a theory that comes under which category?",
        "answer": "(a) Process",
        "options": [
            "(a) Process",
            "(b) Content",
            "(c) Attribution",
            "(d) Perception"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 361,
        "question": "________ contains the theories which give an idea about what employees want or need.",
        "answer": "(d) Content Theory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Expectancy theory",
            "(b) Maslow theory",
            "(c) Process Theory",
            "(d) Content Theory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 362,
        "question": "Which of the following is not an example of Content Theory?",
        "answer": "(c) Expectancy theory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Maslow Theory",
            "(b) Herzberg's Theory",
            "(c) Expectancy theory",
            "(d) Alderfer's ERG theory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 363,
        "question": "Which theory emphasizes that an unsatisfied need can influence behavior, while a satisfied one will not act as a motivator?",
        "answer": "(a) Maslow Theory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Maslow Theory",
            "(b) Herzberg's Theory",
            "(c) Expectancy theory",
            "(d) Alderfer's ERG theory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 364,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a part of the hygiene factor of the two-factor theory?",
        "answer": "(c) Responsibilities",
        "options": [
            "(a) Company policy",
            "(b) Administration",
            "(c) Responsibilities",
            "(d) Interpersonal Relations"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 365,
        "question": "The purpose of job enrichment is to:",
        "answer": "(b) Increase job efficiency",
        "options": [
            "(a) Expand the number of tasks an individual can do",
            "(b) Increase job efficiency",
            "(c) Increase job effectiveness",
            "(d) Increase job satisfaction of middle management"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 366,
        "question": "________ is the process of stimulating people to actions to accomplish the goals.",
        "answer": "(b) Motivation",
        "options": [
            "(a) Bonus",
            "(b) Motivation",
            "(c) Performance-based Incentive",
            "(d) Promotion"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 367,
        "question": "________ is the force of action or motivation.",
        "answer": "(b) Stimulus",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behaviour",
            "(b) Stimulus",
            "(c) Perception",
            "(d) Attitude"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 368,
        "question": "Motivation includes:",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Job enrichment",
            "(b) Job rotation",
            "(c) Job enlargement",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 369,
        "question": "High rate of experienced employees leaving a job increases cost and tends to place less emphasis on:",
        "answer": "(c) Employee Turnover",
        "options": [
            "(a) Training",
            "(b) Absenteeism",
            "(c) Employee Turnover",
            "(d) Strikes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 370,
        "question": "Which of the following is a strategy of job design that increases job depth by meeting employees' needs for psychological growth?",
        "answer": "(b) Job enrichment",
        "options": [
            "(a) Job rotation",
            "(b) Job enrichment",
            "(c) Job enlargement",
            "(d) Job engagement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 371,
        "question": "According to Herzberg, which of the following is a maintenance factor?",
        "answer": "(a) Salary",
        "options": [
            "(a) Salary",
            "(b) Work itself",
            "(c) Responsibility",
            "(d) Recognition"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 372,
        "question": "________, a young Welsh factory owner, was one of the first to emphasize the human needs of employees. He refused to employ young children.",
        "answer": "(c) Robert Owen",
        "options": [
            "(a) Andrew Ure",
            "(b) J.N. Tata",
            "(c) Robert Owen",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 373,
        "question": "The job satisfaction of an employee depends on their:",
        "answer": "(b) Attitude",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behaviour",
            "(b) Attitude",
            "(c) Personality",
            "(d) Employer"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 374,
        "question": "Job satisfaction is related to absenteeism and turnover:",
        "answer": "(b) Negatively",
        "options": [
            "(a) Positively",
            "(b) Negatively",
            "(c) Directly",
            "(d) Elastically"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 375,
        "question": "________ advocated that humans are essentially motivated by levels of needs.",
        "answer": "(a) A. Maslow",
        "options": [
            "(a) A. Maslow",
            "(b) Follett",
            "(c) Elton Mayo",
            "(d) Ivan Pavlov"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 376,
        "question": "In order from lowest to highest, what are Maslow's five classes of needs?",
        "answer": "(c) Physiological-safety-social-esteem-self-actualization",
        "options": [
            "(a) Social-esteem-physiological-safety-self-actualization",
            "(b) Physiological-safety-social-self-actualization-esteem",
            "(c) Physiological-safety-social-esteem-self-actualization",
            "(d) Self-actualization-esteem-safety-social-physiological"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 377,
        "question": "Maslow says that human beings are full of needs and wants. These needs will lead to their:",
        "answer": "(b) Behaviour",
        "options": [
            "(a) Job",
            "(b) Behaviour",
            "(c) Attitude",
            "(d) Motivation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 378,
        "question": "A person will try for the next level need when their ________ is satisfied.",
        "answer": "(a) Basic need",
        "options": [
            "(a) Basic need",
            "(b) Family",
            "(c) Income",
            "(d) Job"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 379,
        "question": "In the needs are arranged in an order as per their importance (basic to complex)",
        "answer": "(a) Maslow need Theory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Maslow need Theory",
            "(b) Herzberg theory",
            "(c) Satisfaction theory",
            "(d) Mayo theory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 380,
        "question": "The individuality, humanness and mental health of the person will improve at the level of need he is satisfied with.",
        "answer": "(c) At par with",
        "options": [
            "(a) Less than",
            "(b) Greater than",
            "(c) At par with",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 381,
        "question": "Salary and basic working conditions will come under",
        "answer": "(b) Physiological needs",
        "options": [
            "(a) Safety needs",
            "(b) Physiological needs",
            "(c) Social needs",
            "(d) Organizational needs"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 382,
        "question": "Which need improves the confidence level of an employee when satisfied?",
        "answer": "(d) Esteem",
        "options": [
            "(a) Social",
            "(b) Safety",
            "(c) Basic",
            "(d) Esteem"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 383,
        "question": "Responsibility, Advancement, etc. are examples of",
        "answer": "(a) Motivators",
        "options": [
            "(a) Motivators",
            "(b) Hygiene factors",
            "(c) Improvement factors",
            "(d) Advance factors"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 384,
        "question": "The higher-order needs specified by Maslow are considered as _______ as per Herzberg.",
        "answer": "(a) Motivators",
        "options": [
            "(a) Motivators",
            "(b) Hygiene factors",
            "(c) Improvement factors",
            "(d) Advanced factors"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 385,
        "question": "Wages and fringe benefits are no longer employees' first priority.",
        "answer": "(c) Rewards",
        "options": [
            "(a) Wages",
            "(b) Bonus",
            "(c) Rewards",
            "(d) Promotions"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 386,
        "question": "A satisfied employee will be a",
        "answer": "(c) High performer",
        "options": [
            "(a) Motivator to others",
            "(b) Manager",
            "(c) High performer",
            "(d) Team Leader"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 387,
        "question": "The success of each organization depends upon the performance of",
        "answer": "(d) Employee",
        "options": [
            "(a) Employer",
            "(b) Management",
            "(c) Vendor",
            "(d) Employee"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 388,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a capability of an employee having a positive attitude?",
        "answer": "(c) Pessimism",
        "options": [
            "(a) Focus",
            "(b) Creativity",
            "(c) Pessimism",
            "(d) Confidence"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 389,
        "question": "Which one is not a benefit to the employee that results from a positive attitude?",
        "answer": "(a) Promotion",
        "options": [
            "(a) Promotion",
            "(b) Less stress",
            "(c) Job security",
            "(d) Enjoying life"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 390,
        "question": "Belief, opinion, knowledge, emotions, feelings, and intention are components of",
        "answer": "(c) Attitude",
        "options": [
            "(a) OB",
            "(b) Job satisfaction",
            "(c) Attitude",
            "(d) Personality"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 391,
        "question": "Components of Attitude can majorly be segregated into how many types?",
        "answer": "(c) 3",
        "options": [
            "(a) 7",
            "(b) 4",
            "(c) 3",
            "(d) 6"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 392,
        "question": "The attitude based on beliefs, opinions, knowledge, or information about a particular event that the employee possesses is under which component of Attitude?",
        "answer": "(b) Cognitive",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behavioral",
            "(b) Cognitive",
            "(c) Affective",
            "(d) Positive"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 393,
        "question": "The attitude based on the concept that 'every individual will have an intention to react in a certain way toward something' is under which component of Attitude?",
        "answer": "(a) Behavioral",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behavioral",
            "(b) Cognitive",
            "(c) Affective",
            "(d) Positive"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 394,
        "question": "The attitude based on feelings, sentiments, and emotions of a person is under which component of Attitude?",
        "answer": "(c) Affective",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behavioral",
            "(b) Cognitive",
            "(c) Affective",
            "(d) Positive"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 395,
        "question": "Which is the only component of attitude that is visible and can be observed directly?",
        "answer": "(a) Behavioral",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behavioral",
            "(b) Cognitive",
            "(c) Affective",
            "(d) Positive"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 396,
        "question": "The statement 'My friends are good' is an example of which component of attitude?",
        "answer": "(b) Cognitive",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behavioral",
            "(b) Cognitive",
            "(c) Affective",
            "(d) Positive"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 397,
        "question": "The statement 'I don't feel comfortable in a crowd' is an example of which component of attitude?",
        "answer": "(c) Affective",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behavioral",
            "(b) Cognitive",
            "(c) Affective",
            "(d) Positive"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 398,
        "question": "The statement 'I am going to apologize for my mistake' is an example of which component of attitude?",
        "answer": "(a) Behavioral",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behavioral",
            "(b) Cognitive",
            "(c) Affective",
            "(d) Positive"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 399,
        "question": "Which component of attitude is a result of family condition, childhood experiences, etc.?",
        "answer": "(c) Affective",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behavioral",
            "(b) Cognitive",
            "(c) Affective",
            "(d) Positive"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 400,
        "question": "Which is not a method used for changing the attitude of an employee?",
        "answer": "(c) Performance appraisal",
        "options": [
            "(a) Use of fear",
            "(b) Providing new information",
            "(c) Performance appraisal",
            "(d) Giving feedback"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 401,
        "question": "Among the following, which is not a problem in changing the attitude of the employee?",
        "answer": "(b) Resistant by employee",
        "options": [
            "(a) Insufficient information",
            "(b) Resistant by employee",
            "(c) Cognitive ",
            "(d) Cognitive dissonance"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 402,
        "question": "Psychological process by which individuals organize and interpret their sensory impressions in order to give meaning to their environment is the definition of",
        "answer": "(c) Perception",
        "options": [
            "(a) Attitude",
            "(b) Thinking",
            "(c) Perception",
            "(d) Personality"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 403,
        "question": "A process of receiving, selecting, organizing, interpreting, checking, and reacting to sensory stimuli or data so as to form a meaningful and coherent picture of the world is",
        "answer": "(c) Perception",
        "options": [
            "(a) Attitude",
            "(b) Thinking",
            "(c) Perception",
            "(d) Communication"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 404,
        "question": "The theory states that the human mind will receive or accept only those information which it feels are relevant.",
        "answer": "(b) Selective Perception",
        "options": [
            "(a) Perception theory",
            "(b) Selective Perception",
            "(c) Relevance Theory",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 405,
        "question": "____ deals with how the social perceiver uses information to arrive at causal explanations for events.",
        "answer": "(a) Attribution theory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Attribution theory",
            "(b) Social Perception Theory",
            "(c) Selective Perception",
            "(d) Social Theory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 406,
        "question": "____ is the sequence of psychological steps that a person uses to organize and interpret information from the outside world.",
        "answer": "(a) Perceptual process",
        "options": [
            "(a) Perceptual process",
            "(b) Thinking process",
            "(c) Selection Process",
            "(d) Sequential theory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 407,
        "question": "Which of the following is not a step in the perceptual process?",
        "answer": "(c) Perception",
        "options": [
            "(a) Object",
            "(b) Selection",
            "(c) Perception",
            "(d) Response"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 408,
        "question": "\"The combination of characteristics or qualities that form an individual's distinctive character\" is the definition of",
        "answer": "(a) Personality",
        "options": [
            "(a) Personality",
            "(b) Motivation",
            "(c) Attitude",
            "(d) Behavior"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 409,
        "question": "The family condition and impact of the parents is the main base for the personality of a person. Later it might change by",
        "answer": "(b) External influences",
        "options": [
            "(a) Thinking",
            "(b) External influences",
            "(c) Own ability",
            "(d) Learning experiences"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 410,
        "question": "Every individual is _______ by their personality.",
        "answer": "(c) Unique",
        "options": [
            "(a) Intellectual",
            "(b) Specific",
            "(c) Unique",
            "(d) Systematic"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 411,
        "question": "Sometimes due to any hard situation ________ change but will take a long time.",
        "answer": "(d) Personality",
        "options": [
            "(a) Objective",
            "(b) Attitude",
            "(c) Motivation",
            "(d) Personality"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 412,
        "question": "From the below, which is not an outcome from a person having a good personality?",
        "answer": "(d) Make Profit",
        "options": [
            "(a) Good Performer",
            "(b) Good team player",
            "(c) Lead a team well",
            "(d) Make Profit"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 413,
        "question": "The five personality traits as per Big Five Personality Traits are:",
        "answer": "(a) Extroversion, Agreeableness, Conscientiousness, Emotional Stability, Openness to experience",
        "options": [
            "(a) Extroversion, Agreeableness, Conscientiousness, Emotional Stability, Openness to experience",
            "(b) Extroversion, Agreeableness, Friendly, Emotional Stability, Openness to experience",
            "(c) Extroversion, Agreeableness, Courage, Friendly, Openness to experience",
            "(d) Extroversion, Agreeableness, Conscientiousness, Emotional Stability, Easy going"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 414,
        "question": "Outgoing, talkative, and social are part of which personality trait as per Big Five Personality Traits?",
        "answer": "(d) Extroversion",
        "options": [
            "(a) Friendly",
            "(b) Openness to experience",
            "(c) Introversion",
            "(d) Extroversion"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 415,
        "question": "Trust, nature, and cooperative are part of which personality trait as per Big Five Personality Traits?",
        "answer": "(a) Agreeableness",
        "options": [
            "(a) Agreeableness",
            "(b) Emotional Stability",
            "(c) Openness to experience",
            "(d) Introversion"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 416,
        "question": "Dependable and responsible are part of which personality trait as per Big Five Personality Traits?",
        "answer": "(b) Conscientiousness",
        "options": [
            "(a) Agreeableness",
            "(b) Conscientiousness",
            "(c) Openness to experience",
            "(d) Introversion"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 417,
        "question": "Relaxed and secure are part of which personality trait as per Big Five Personality Traits?",
        "answer": "(d) Emotional Stability",
        "options": [
            "(a) Agreeableness",
            "(b) Emotional Stability",
            "(c) Openness to experience",
            "(d) Introversion"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 418,
        "question": "Sensitive and intellectual are part of which personality trait as per Big Five Personality Traits?",
        "answer": "(c) Openness to experience",
        "options": [
            "(a) Agreeableness",
            "(b) Emotional Stability",
            "(c) Openness to experience",
            "(d) Introversion"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 419,
        "question": "______ are the theories which give an idea about what employees want or need and what are the key factors the managers can utilize to motivate the employees.",
        "answer": "(d) Content Theory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Maslow theory",
            "(b) Herzberg Theory",
            "(c) Process Theory",
            "(d) Content Theory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 420,
        "question": "_____ theory states the ways or processes by which the needs can be converted into behavior or performance.",
        "answer": "(c) Process Theory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Maslow theory",
            "(b) Expectancy Theory",
            "(c) Process Theory",
            "(d) Content Theory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 421,
        "question": "Organizational behavior is a field of study backed by a body of _____ associated with growing concern for people at the workplace.",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Theory",
            "(b) Research",
            "(c) Application",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 422,
        "question": "____ are stimulated by events and people external to themselves. They show their feelings, learn by talking, and work well in groups.",
        "answer": "(c) Extroverts",
        "options": [
            "(a) Private personalities",
            "(b) Introverts",
            "(c) Extroverts",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 423,
        "question": "____ prefers private reflection, self-examination, and self-discovery. They hide their feelings, prefer to work alone, and learn by watching.",
        "answer": "(b) Introverts",
        "options": [
            "(a) Private personalities",
            "(b) Introverts",
            "(c) Extroverts",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 424,
        "question": "MBTI tests the personalities in ____ categories.",
        "answer": "(b) 4",
        "options": [
            "(a) 3",
            "(b) 4",
            "(c) 5",
            "(d) 6"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 425,
        "question": "As per MBTI personality, people like real-life examples, prefer practical exercises, and get the facts while possibly missing the main idea.",
        "answer": "(b) Sensing",
        "options": [
            "(a) Introversion",
            "(b) Sensing",
            "(c) Intuition",
            "(d) Thinking"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 426,
        "question": "As per MBTI personality, people work based on hunches and feelings, use their imagination, and get the main idea while missing some of the facts.",
        "answer": "(c) Intuition",
        "options": [
            "(a) Introversion",
            "(b) Sensing",
            "(c) Intuition",
            "(d) Thinking"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 427,
        "question": "As per MBTI personality, people take a laid back, relaxed approach. They're flexible, open to change, and like to explore.",
        "answer": "(c) Perceiving",
        "options": [
            "(a) Introversion",
            "(b) Sensing",
            "(c) Perceiving",
            "(d) Thinking"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 428,
        "question": "Social learning is an extension of",
        "answer": "(b) Operant learning",
        "options": [
            "(a) Cognitive learning",
            "(b) Operant learning",
            "(c) Classical conditioning",
            "(d) Programmed learning"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 429,
        "question": "Basis of \"Collegial Model of OB\" is",
        "answer": "(d) Partnership",
        "options": [
            "(a) Economic resources",
            "(b) Power",
            "(c) Leadership",
            "(d) Partnership"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 430,
        "question": "____ is our perception of one personality trait influences how we view a person's entire personality.",
        "answer": "(b) Halo effect",
        "options": [
            "(a) Perception",
            "(b) Halo effect",
            "(c) Stereotyping",
            "(d) Individual Personality"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 431,
        "question": "A major problem with a task force type of management is",
        "answer": "(b) Its status is too inflexible",
        "options": [
            "(a) There is no logical basis for task force information",
            "(b) Its status is too inflexible",
            "(c) Lack of accountability",
            "(d) Lack of planning"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 432,
        "question": "____ embodies a team concept, is based on the principle of mutual contribution by employer and employees.",
        "answer": "(d) Collegial Model",
        "options": [
            "(a) Autocratic model",
            "(b) Custodial model",
            "(c) Supportive Model",
            "(d) Collegial Model"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 433,
        "question": "A manager with good ____ can make the workplace more pleasant.",
        "answer": "(d) Interpersonal Skills",
        "options": [
            "(a) Communication",
            "(b) Knowledge",
            "(c) Experience",
            "(d) Interpersonal Skills"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 434,
        "question": "Groups created by managerial decision in order to accomplish stated goals of the organization are called",
        "answer": "(a) Formal groups",
        "options": [
            "(a) Formal groups",
            "(b) Informal groups",
            "(c) Task groups",
            "(d) Interest groups"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 435,
        "question": "Continued membership in a group will usually require",
        "answer": "(b) Conforming to group norms",
        "options": [
            "(a) Supporting the group leader",
            "(b) Conforming to group norms",
            "(c) Encouraging cohesiveness in the group",
            "(d) Developing a status system"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 436,
        "question": "A lack of clarity concerning what will happen is referred to as",
        "answer": "(c) Uncertainty",
        "options": [
            "(a) Temporal",
            "(b) Predisposition",
            "(c) Uncertainty",
            "(d) Negation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 437,
        "question": "Stereotyping generally affects the",
        "answer": "(c) Interpersonal Relations",
        "options": [
            "(a) Organization Structure",
            "(b) Behavior",
            "(c) Interpersonal Relations",
            "(d) Communication"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 438,
        "question": "\"Girls are not good at sports\" is an example of",
        "answer": "(c) Stereotyping",
        "options": [
            "(a) Perception",
            "(b) Halo effect",
            "(c) Stereotyping",
            "(d) Individual Personality"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 439,
        "question": "Organization structure primarily refers to",
        "answer": "(a) How activities are coordinated & controlled",
        "options": [
            "(a) How activities are coordinated & controlled",
            "(b) How resources are allocated",
            "(c) The location of departments and office space",
            "(d) The policy statements developed by the firm"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 440,
        "question": "Scientists of OB recognize that organizations are not static but dynamic and _____",
        "answer": "(c) Ever changing",
        "options": [
            "(a) Processing",
            "(b) Systematic",
            "(c) Ever changing",
            "(d) Researching"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 441,
        "question": "Concerning organizational cultures, the stronger the culture, the more influential it is on employee behavior.",
        "answer": "(d) The stronger the culture, the more influential it is on employee behavior",
        "options": [
            "(a) A strong culture is a more productive environment",
            "(b) A weak culture is a more productive environment",
            "(c) The specific culture that contributes to positive effectiveness is well known",
            "(d) The stronger the culture, the more influential it is on employee behavior"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 442,
        "question": "Employees with relatively weak higher-order needs are concerned with variety and autonomy. [55] is",
        "answer": "(a) less",
        "options": [
            "(a) less",
            "(b) more",
            "(c) very",
            "(d) extremely"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 443,
        "question": "Which of the following best explains why an employee behaves as s/he does?",
        "answer": "(b) Both the environment and individual differences are important considerations in understanding individual employee behavior.",
        "options": [
            "(a) The environment is the most important consideration in understanding individual employee behavior.",
            "(b) Both the environment and individual differences are important considerations in understanding individual employee behavior.",
            "(c) Neither the environment nor individual differences are important considerations in understanding individual employee behavior.",
            "(d) Employee personality and attitudes are primarily dictated by the environment."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 444,
        "question": "What is the key word in understanding organization structure?",
        "answer": "(a) Control",
        "options": [
            "(a) Control",
            "(b) Change",
            "(c) Process",
            "(d) Delegation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 445,
        "question": "A program that asks managers to reconsider how work would be done and the organization structured if they were starting to develop the company from the beginning is:",
        "answer": "(a) reengineering",
        "options": [
            "(a) reengineering",
            "(b) MBO",
            "(c) TQM",
            "(d) Diversity training"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 446,
        "question": "Organization structures ______",
        "answer": "(d) can be defined simply as activities that occur regularly",
        "options": [
            "(a) affect group behavior more than individual behavior",
            "(b) change rapidly to meet environmental and market changes",
            "(c) contribute positively to organizational performance",
            "(d) can be defined simply as activities that occur regularly"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 447,
        "question": "Shared organizational values are:",
        "answer": "(c) different for the various components of a diverse workforce",
        "options": [
            "(a) unconscious, affective desires or wants that guide society's behavior",
            "(b) influenced by international values",
            "(c) different for the various components of a diverse workforce",
            "(d) a myth"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 448,
        "question": "The definition of communication implies that",
        "answer": "(d) understanding must occur to have communication",
        "options": [
            "(a) communication is mostly verbal",
            "(b) communication is mostly written",
            "(c) most communication is in a vertical direction",
            "(d) understanding must occur to have communication"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 449,
        "question": "The least used communication channel in an organization is usually",
        "answer": "(d) Horizontal",
        "options": [
            "(a) upward",
            "(b) downward",
            "(c) diagonal",
            "(d) Horizontal"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 450,
        "question": "Individuals such as Albert Einstein, Edwin Land, and Steve Jobs lead through which type of power?",
        "answer": "(c) Expert",
        "options": [
            "(a) Legitimate",
            "(b) Reward",
            "(c) Expert",
            "(d) Charismatic"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 451,
        "question": "If modern-day managers do not positively address and manage workforce diversity, which of the following may become negative outcomes for an organization except",
        "answer": "(a) more difficult communication",
        "options": [
            "(a) more difficult communication",
            "(b) Increased creativity and innovation",
            "(c) more interpersonal conflicts",
            "(d) potential for higher employee turnover"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 452,
        "question": "The structure of an OB model includes 3 levels of analysis: individual, group, and organizational systems. Issues that influence all 3 levels in various ways and thus affect behavioral dynamics are",
        "answer": "(a) change and stress",
        "options": [
            "(a) change and stress",
            "(b) Organizational culture and commitment",
            "(c) Power and politics",
            "(d) Work design and technology"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 453,
        "question": "What is the meaning of cultural diversity in the context of organizational behavior?",
        "answer": "(a) A lack of uniformity and variation in language, food, culture, living, religion, etc.",
        "options": [
            "(a) A lack of uniformity and variation in language, food, culture, living, religion, etc.",
            "(b) A lack of diversity in the workplace.",
            "(c) A lack of diversity in the community.",
            "(d) None of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 454,
        "question": "What are the forces affecting organizational behavior?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) People",
            "(b) Environment",
            "(c) Technology",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 455,
        "question": "What are the challenges for organizational behavior in the present context?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Employee expectation",
            "(b) Workforce diversity",
            "(c) Globalization",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 456,
        "question": "What is the relationship between Edward Tolman and organizational behavior?",
        "answer": "(a) Behaviorist Framework",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behaviorist Framework",
            "(b) Cognitive approach",
            "(c) Social Cognitive Framework",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 457,
        "question": "What is the meaning of motivation in the context of organizational behavior?",
        "answer": "(d) A set of forces that energize, direct, and sustain behavior.",
        "options": [
            "(a) A lack of uniformity and variation in language, food, culture, living, religion, etc.",
            "(b) A lack of diversity in the workplace.",
            "(c) A lack of diversity in the community.",
            "(d) A set of forces that energize, direct, and sustain behavior."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 458,
        "question": "What is the achievement motive?",
        "answer": "(a) The desire to achieve success and avoid failure.",
        "options": [
            "(a) The desire to achieve success and avoid failure.",
            "(b) The desire to achieve success and embrace failure.",
            "(c) The desire to avoid success and avoid failure.",
            "(d) The desire to avoid success and embrace failure."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 459,
        "question": "What are the theories of work motivation?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Maslow's Hierarchy of Needs",
            "(b) Herzberg's Two-Factor Theory",
            "(c) McClelland's Theory of Needs",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 460,
        "question": "What is the importance of motivation in the workplace?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Increases productivity",
            "(b) Improves employee morale",
            "(c) Reduces employee turnover",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 461,
        "question": "What is the relationship between motivation and job satisfaction?",
        "answer": "(d) Both a) and b)",
        "options": [
            "(a) Motivation leads to job satisfaction.",
            "(b) Job satisfaction leads to motivation.",
            "(c) There is no relationship between motivation and job satisfaction.",
            "(d) Both a) and b)"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 462,
        "question": "What are the determinants of personality?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Heredity",
            "(b) Environment",
            "(c) Situation",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 463,
        "question": "What is the Big Five Trait Theory?",
        "answer": "(a) A theory that identifies five broad dimensions of personality: openness, conscientiousness, extraversion, agreeableness, and neuroticism.",
        "options": [
            "(a) A theory that identifies five broad dimensions of personality: openness, conscientiousness, extraversion, agreeableness, and neuroticism.",
            "(b) A theory that identifies five narrow dimensions of personality: intelligence, creativity, motivation, empathy, and resilience.",
            "(c) A theory that identifies five broad dimensions of personality: intelligence, creativity, motivation, empathy, and resilience.",
            "(d) None of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 464,
        "question": "What is the Locus of Control?",
        "answer": "(a) A personality trait that describes the extent to which people believe they have control over their lives.",
        "options": [
            "(a) A personality trait that describes the extent to which people believe they have control over their lives.",
            "(b) A personality trait that describes the extent to which people believe they have no control over their lives.",
            "(c) A personality trait that describes the extent to which people believe they have control over other people's lives.",
            "(d) None of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 465,
        "question": "What is Type A and Type B theory of personality?",
        "answer": "(a) A theory that describes two types of personalities: Type A and Type B.",
        "options": [
            "(a) A theory that describes two types of personalities: Type A and Type B.",
            "(b) A theory that describes two types of personalities: Type A and Type C.",
            "(c) A theory that describes two types of personalities: Type B and Type C.",
            "(d) None of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 466,
        "question": "What are the theories of personality trait and type theories?",
        "answer": "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
        "options": [
            "(a) Trait theory",
            "(b) Type theory",
            "(c) Both (a) and (b)",
            "(d) None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 467,
        "question": "What is the meaning of work stress?",
        "answer": "(c) A state of mental or emotional strain or tension resulting from adverse or demanding circumstances at work.",
        "options": [
            "(a) A lack of uniformity and variation in language, food, culture, living, religion, etc.",
            "(b) A lack of diversity in the workplace.",
            "(c) A state of mental or emotional strain or tension resulting from adverse or demanding circumstances at work.",
            "(d) None of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 468,
        "question": "What are the symptoms of stress?",
        "answer": "(e) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Physical symptoms",
            "(b) Behavioral symptoms",
            "(c) Emotional symptoms",
            "(d) Cognitive symptoms",
            "(e) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 469,
        "question": "What are the sources of stress?",
        "answer": "(e) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Individual level",
            "(b) Group level",
            "(c) Organizational level",
            "(d) Extra-organizational stressors",
            "(e) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 470,
        "question": "What are the stressors?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Physical stressors",
            "(b) Psychological stressors",
            "(c) Organizational stressors",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 471,
        "question": "What is the effect of stress burnouts?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Exhaustion",
            "(b) Cynicism",
            "(c) Inefficacy",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 472,
        "question": "What are the stress management individual strategies?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Time management",
            "(b) Relaxation techniques",
            "(c) Exercise",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 473,
        "question": "What is the meaning of group behavior in the context of organizational behavior?",
        "answer": "(a) The study of how people interact in groups.",
        "options": [
            "(a) The study of how people interact in groups, with their environment",
            "(b) The study of how people interact",
            "(c) The study of how people interact with technology.",
            "(d) None of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 474,
        "question": "What are the leadership styles?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Autocratic",
            "(b) Democratic",
            "(c) Laissez-faire",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 475,
        "question": "What are the traits of effective leaders?",
        "answer": "(d) All of the above",
        "options": [
            "(a) Intelligence",
            "(b) Confidence",
            "(c) Integrity",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 476,
        "question": "What Is autocratic leadership?",
        "answer": "(a) A leadership style where the leader makes decisions without input from others.",
        "options": [
            "(a) A leadership style where the leader makes decisions without input from others.",
            "(b) A leadership style where the leader seeks input from others before making decisions.",
            "(c) A leadership style where the leader delegates decision-making to others.",
            "(d) None of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 477,
        "question": "What is democratic leadership?",
        "answer": "(b) A leadership style where the leader seeks input from others before making decisions.",
        "options": [
            "(a) A leadership style where the leader makes decisions without input from others.",
            "(b) A leadership style where the leader seeks input from others before making decisions.",
            "(c) A leadership style where the leader delegates decision-making to others.",
            "(d) None of the above."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 478,
        "question": "What is laissez-faire leadership?",
        "answer": "(d) A leadership style where the leader provides little guidance or direction.",
        "options": [
            "(a) A leadership style where the leader makes decisions without input from others.",
            "(b) A leadership style where the leader seeks input from others before making decisions.",
            "(c) A leadership style where the leader delegates decision-making to others.",
            "(d) A leadership style where the leader provides little guidance or direction."
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 479,
        "question": "The charismatic leaders are likely to:",
        "answer": "(a) Invoke high performance among followers",
        "options": [
            "(a) Invoke high performance among followers",
            "(b) Encourage women to seek leadership positions",
            "(c) Motivate followers to become more extroverted",
            "(d) Avoid media attention regarding their achievements"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 480,
        "question": "Legitimate power is based on which of the following element?",
        "answer": "(c) Structural position.",
        "options": [
            "(a) Positive rewards",
            "(b) Interpersonal trust",
            "(c) Structural position.",
            "(d) Expert knowledge"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 481,
        "question": "Organization structure primarily refers to",
        "answer": "(a) how activities are coordinated & controlled",
        "options": [
            "(a) how activities are coordinated & controlled",
            "(b) how resources are allocated",
            "(c) the location of departments and office space",
            "(d) the policy statements developed by the firm"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 482,
        "question": "The purpose of job enrichment is to",
        "answer": "(c) Increase job effectiveness",
        "options": [
            "(a) expand the number of tasks an individual can do",
            "(b) Increase job efficiency",
            "(c) Increase job effectiveness",
            "(d) increase job satisfaction of middle management"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 483,
        "question": "Strategic planning as a broad concept consists of",
        "answer": "(b) strategy formulation and strategy implementation",
        "options": [
            "(a) corporate strategy and business strategy",
            "(b) strategy formulation and strategy implementation",
            "(c) inputs and outputs",
            "(d) environmental analysis and internal analysis"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 484,
        "question": "According to Herzberg, which of the following is a maintenance factor?",
        "answer": "(d) Recognition",
        "options": [
            "(a) Salary",
            "(b) Work itself",
            "(c) Responsibility",
            "(d) Recognition"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 485,
        "question": "A major problem with a task force type of management is",
        "answer": "(b) its status is too inflexible",
        "options": [
            "(a) there is no logical basis for task force information",
            "(b) its status is too inflexible",
            "(c) accountability",
            "(d) lack of planning"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 486,
        "question": "Individuals such as Albert Einstein, Edwin Land and Steven Jobs lead through which type of power?",
        "answer": "(c) Expert",
        "options": [
            "(a) Legitimate",
            "(b) Reward",
            "(c) Expert",
            "(d) Charismatic"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 487,
        "question": "The problem-solving process begins with",
        "answer": "(c) Identification of the difficulty",
        "options": [
            "(a) clarification of the situation",
            "(b) establishment of alternatives",
            "(c) Identification of the difficulty",
            "(d) isolation of the cause"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 488,
        "question": "Functional managers are responsible",
        "answer": "(a) for a single area of activity",
        "options": [
            "(a) for a single area of activity",
            "(b) to the upper level of management and staff",
            "(c) for complex organizational sub-units",
            "(d) for obtaining copyrights and patents for newly developed processes and equipment"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 489,
        "question": "Policies are sometimes defined as a(n):",
        "answer": "(d) substitute for management authority",
        "options": [
            "(a) shortcut for thinking",
            "(b) action plan",
            "(c) substitute for strategy",
            "(d) substitute for management authority"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 490,
        "question": "Contribution/s of human relations movement is/are",
        "answer": "(d) All of these",
        "options": [
            "(a) Great Depression",
            "(b) Labour Movement",
            "(c) Hawthorne Studies",
            "(d) All of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 491,
        "question": "Organizational behaviour is a field of study backed by a body of",
        "answer": "(a) Theory",
        "options": [
            "(a) Theory",
            "(b) Research",
            "(c) Application",
            "(d) All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 492,
        "question": "Scientist of OB recognize that organisations are not static but",
        "answer": "(c) ever changing",
        "options": [
            "(a) Processing",
            "(b) systematic",
            "(c) ever changing",
            "(d) researching"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 493,
        "question": "Managerial orientation of \"Autocratic Model\" of OB is",
        "answer": "(a) Authority",
        "options": [
            "(a) Authority",
            "(b) Money",
            "(c) Support",
            "(d) Teamwork"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 494,
        "question": "The problem-solving process begins with:",
        "answer": "(c) Identification of the difficulty",
        "options": [
            "(a) clarification of the situation",
            "(b) establishment of alternatives",
            "(c) Identification of the difficulty",
            "(d) isolation of the cause"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 495,
        "question": "Contribution/s of human relations movement is/are",
        "answer": "(d) All of these",
        "options": [
            "(a) Great Depression",
            "(b) Labour Movement",
            "(c) Hawthorne Studies",
            "(d) All of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 496,
        "question": "Edward Tolman is related to:",
        "answer": "(b) Cognitive approach",
        "options": [
            "(a) Behaviorist Framework",
            "(b) Cognitive approach",
            "(c) Social Cognitive Framework",
            "(d) None of these"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 497,
        "question": "Just-in-Time (JIT) is about supplying customers with what they want when they want it.",
        "answer": "(d) JIT",
        "options": [
            "(a) JUT",
            "(b) HET",
            "(c) JAT",
            "(d) JIT"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 498,
        "question": "Hawthorne Studies is related to which stage of the organizational behaviour evolution",
        "answer": "(d) Human relations movement",
        "options": [
            "(a) Industrial revolution",
            "(b) Scientific management",
            "(c) Organizational behaviour",
            "(d) Human relations movement"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 499,
        "question": "Deming's 4 step cycle for improvement is",
        "answer": "(a) plan, do, check, act",
        "options": [
            "(a) plan, do, check, act",
            "(b) schedule, do, act, check",
            "(c) do, act, check, monitor",
            "(d) plan, control, act, sustain"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 500,
        "question": "A strong organizational culture increases behavioral consistency and, therefore, can act as a substitute for:",
        "answer": "(d) Formalization.",
        "options": [
            "(a) Followership",
            "(b) Socialization",
            "(c) Institutionalization",
            "(d) Formalization."
        ]
    },
]